<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
Rod Brind’Amour, the scar-faced former N.H.L. center who is the first-year coach of the Carolina Hurricanes, was talking the other day about winning and losing — specifically, how he enjoys winning less than he should, and how losing still stinks, although he used another word.

“I don’t know that when I played, I had that much joy,” said Brind’Amour, who scored 452 goals in a 20-year N.H.L. career and was the captain of the Carolina team that won the Stanley Cup in 2006. “I was always chasing something, or always thinking about the next one. Now I get to see these guys, and I’m enjoying it — how they’ve responded, how they’re enjoying the run.”
 </BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
TORONTO — The Maple Leafs superstars John Tavares and Auston Matthews have been as good as advertised this season, and often even better.

But Mitch Marner, who came to this championship-starved city with high expectations after he was chosen with the No. 4 overall pick in 2015, has had a breakout year and made a case that he’s the most valuable Maple Leafs forward.

Marner, a 21-year-old winger, led Toronto in points this season and became the youngest player in Maple Leafs history to record 90 points, the first to hit that benchmark in 22 years.

Marner finished 11th in the N.H.L. with 94 points (26 goals and 68 assists), six points ahead of Tavares and 21 ahead of Matthews, who missed 14 games because of injury. Marner and Tavares play on the same line, and Marner was a key reason Tavares, in his first season in Toronto, had a career-high 47 goals this season.
 </BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
AMHERST, Mass. — When Coach Greg Carvel arrived at University of Massachusetts-Amherst from St. Lawrence University in 2016, he inherited a hockey program that had just two winning seasons since 1995 and had won only 11 conference games in Hockey East the previous three seasons.

“We were the joke of Hockey East for a while there,” said Kurt Keats, the only senior on the team who has been in the program for four years. “We definitely were not a source of pride for the university.”

But this season, the Minutemen won their first Hockey East regular-season title and advanced to their first men’s Frozen Four.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
The luck of the draw helped the Devils take a step in that direction Tuesday.

The Devils will pick first at June’s N.H.L. draft after the lottery balls fell in their favor — bumping the franchise up to the top spot from No. 3.

Shero would not tip his hand after the order was revealed, but the presumptive No. 1 pick, Jack Hughes, was already on everyone’s mind.

“I’ve seen Jack play a long time,” Shero said of the 17-year-old center who plays for the United States National Development Team. “We recognize Jack’s a great young player.”
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
“They remind me of the Dallas Cowboys in their heyday,” said Burke, who won a Stanley Cup as general manager of the Anaheim Ducks in 2007. “No weaknesses and a lot of star power.”

Tampa Bay went on to beat Toronto that night, 3-1, and two days later, closed out the Boston Bruins, 6-3, for its record-tying 62nd win this season.

With a 62-16-4 record, the Lightning tied the 1995-96 Red Wings for the most wins in a season. And Tampa Bay, with 128 points, fell just short of one huge benchmark — the record 132 points achieved by the 1976-77 Montreal Canadiens (60-8-12), who were regarded as one of the best, if not the best, N.H.L. teams ever.

Tampa Bay finished with 12 more wins, and 21 more points, than the next closest team, the Calgary Flames. The Lightning did not lose more than two consecutive games all season.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
GREENBURGH, N.Y. — Henrik Lundqvist looked around the Rangers’ dressing room before a late-season home game and wearily shook his head. Perhaps the most difficult season of his 14-year N.H.L. career was winding down, and the reality of missing the playoffs for the second straight spring had long since set in.

“It’s been tough,” he said. “Draining.”

Lundqvist, the Rangers’ longtime goalie, could not be blamed for his visible angst. His team finished 32-36-14.

Lundqvist, 37, has seen many teammates depart for other teams, but the trade of Mats Zuccarello to Dallas in late February seemed an emotional tipping point. Lundqvist was brought to tears after the next day’s game, an overtime loss at Washington.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
Heading for the playoffs in his first season behind the Islanders’ bench, Coach Barry Trotz has found chemistry with Long Island, his presence undoubtedly a tonic for players and the team’s fervent fan base.

Trotz speaks of being recognized when running errands, often greeted with high-fives and photo requests. He mentions visiting a local Home Depot, where an enthusiastic fan shopping with her daughters recognized him and was so enthralled that she spontaneously hugged him.

“You talk about special people. Joining the Islander family and living on the Island has been special,” said Trotz, 56, a father of four in his 20th season as an N.H.L. coach. “You want to build a foundation, establish a culture that’s not a one-year thing. You want a certain standard.”

Trotz has helped set a new standard with the Islanders since joining the team after capturing the Stanley Cup last June with the Washington Capitals.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
On the day after February’s trade deadline stripped the Rangers of three key veterans, David Quinn’s whistle pierced the practice rink air. The coach barked with the rasp of a well-worn instructor’s voice, “That can’t happen.” The Rangers reran the drill, which Quinn this time punctuated with “good job.”

An hour into the session, Quinn skated in to speak quietly with Brendan Lemieux during a defensive routine. Lemieux, the 23-year-old prospect acquired in a trade for Kevin Hayes, had met Quinn only that morning after joining from the Winnipeg Jets.

“That’s what was really cool about my first practice,” Lemieux said afterward. “I was already learning things, being taught. I guess that goes to what kind of coach he is. He’s a teacher. There are a lot of N.H.L. coaches that aren’t like that.”

With the Rangers more than a year into a rebuild, teaching a young team has been Quinn’s primary objective. Ten players on the Rangers’ roster are 23 or younger. Entering the final game of the season, the Rangers have just four wins in 19 games since the trade deadline on Feb. 25, though seven losses were by a single goal, including five in overtime or a shootout.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
In many ways, there has never been a better time to be a member of the United States women’s national hockey team.

Two years after the players threatened to boycott the world championship tournament over pay equity, U.S.A. Hockey, the national governing body, is paying them more than ever, about $71,000 each annually.

On the ice, the American women have continued to exceed the achievements of the men’s national team and won their second Olympic gold medal in a stirring final against Canada.

Members of the team have skated in the skills competition at N.H.L. All-Star weekend and served as analysts for N.H.L. television broadcasts. Participation in the sport among girls and women is skyrocketing.

But halfway through the labor contract with U.S.A. Hockey signed in March 2017, as the national team begins its pursuit of a fifth straight world championship in Finland this week, its players wonder whether the future of their sport is as bright as the present. Those concerns grew after the Canadian Women’s Hockey League, one of two professional leagues in North America, announced Sunday it would fold in May.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
In a sudden blow to women’s professional sports in North America, the Canadian Women’s Hockey League announced on Sunday that it would discontinue operations on May 1.

The C.W.H.L., founded in 2007, operated as a centrally funded, nonprofit enterprise. It included some of the sport’s biggest stars, like Hilary Knight and Marie-Philip Poulin.

Laurel Walzak, chairwoman of the league’s board of directors, said that the C.W.H.L.’s management had realized in the past few weeks that funding would not be available to continue next season.

“We realized this model is no longer viable in the economics and the future of the C.W.H.L.,” Walzak said. “We voted on this Friday night.”
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
Alexandar Georgiev, an undersized goaltender no team seemed to want, was not supposed to get here.

Yet there he was on Feb. 10 at Madison Square Garden, repeatedly foiling the Toronto Maple Leafs’ shooting barrage. In all, Georgiev, an undrafted rookie, made a career-high 55 saves, carrying the Rangers to a 4-1 victory in a nationally televised game on his 23rd birthday.

It was the second-most saves for a goalie during a regular-season game in franchise history, after Mike Richter’s 59 on Jan. 31, 1991, but Georgiev was not upset with his teammates over all the rubber he faced.

“No. No. No,” Georgiev said in a recent interview. “It was a great day to be a goalie for the New York Rangers. It was fun.”

It has been a season of trying to look on the bright side for the rebuilding Rangers, who were sellers for a second consecutive trade deadline and will miss the playoffs for the second consecutive year. They have received various future assets, including young players and draft picks, and are in the process of evaluating and developing their young core.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
For many years, the N.C.A.A. Division I men’s hockey tournament was a celebration of the sport’s aristocracy.

Increasingly, it is becoming a demonstration of the sport’s parity.

Of the 16 teams in this year’s tournament, which begins Friday, only six have won a national championship.

Arizona State, in only its third season playing a full Division I schedule, is the first independent to make the tournament in 27 years. Another first-time participant is American International College, a school of less than 2,000 undergraduates in Springfield, Mass.

Bowling Green State is in the tournament for the first time since 1990; the University of Massachusetts for the first time since 2007.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
MONTREAL — Fred Sasakamoose thought this day would never come.

Sasakamoose, the N.H.L.’s first Indigenous player when he skated in 11 games with the Chicago Black Hawks during the 1953-54 season, watched from the Ahtahkakoop Cree Nation in northern Saskatchewan on Sunday night as the Montreal Canadiens battled the Carolina Hurricanes — and heard his own language.

It was the first N.H.L. broadcast in Plains Cree, the Algonquian language he grew up speaking.

“It makes me so proud that they’re going to broadcast the game in my language,” he said in a telephone interview before the game.

“I heard people broadcast local tournaments, the Indian Stanley Cup they call them. This evening I am going to listen to the game and understand, because I’m a Cree Indian.”
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
This weekend is Wisconsin forward Annie Pankowski’s last shot to go out a winner in college hockey.

She is a three-time finalist for the Patty Kazmaier Award, which will be given out Saturday to the best female player in college hockey. She has never won.

On Friday, she will play in the Frozen Four with the Wisconsin Badgers for the fourth time. She has never won a national championship.

Top-seeded Wisconsin (33-4-2) faces the two-time defending champion Clarkson (30-7-2) on Friday in the semifinals at Quinnipiac University in Hamden, Conn., with Minnesota (31-5-1) and Cornell (24-5-6) vying to play the winner. The title game is Sunday.

“All the previous Frozen Fours have been different, but this one is my last,” Pankowski, 24, said. “As a team, we’re really hungry to win it.”
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
Last weekend, the Metropolitan Riveters nearly re-enacted “Planes, Trains and Automobiles” trying to reach their semifinal game of the National Women’s Hockey League playoffs.

The Riveters dealt with predawn alarms; being momentarily stranded in Charlotte, N.C.; and losing most of their equipment. The game, against the Minnesota Whitecaps in St. Paul, scheduled for last Sunday, was postponed. The semifinal will now be played Friday night in St. Paul, with the Isobel Cup final scheduled for two days later at the same rink.

The N.W.H.L., in its fourth season, has had travel-and weather-related postponements before, as have other professional leagues like the W.N.B.A. Despite partnerships with four N.H.L. franchises, N.W.H.L. teams still travel with budgetary and time constraints.

Some Riveters players who expected to play last Sunday will not be available for the rescheduled game because they cannot take the day off from their full-time jobs.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
MINNEAPOLIS — The Minnesota Whitecaps, the newest and possibly best team in the National Women’s Hockey League, occasionally practice in an arena that is the closest thing to a women’s hockey museum in this hockey-loving state.

Ridder Arena, home of the University of Minnesota women’s team, features sprawling murals high at each end, honoring the program’s Olympians and All-Americans. The Whitecaps stars Lee Stecklein and Hannah Brandt, gold medalists for the 2018 United States Olympic team, appear on both. And the All-American mural includes one of the Whitecaps co-coaches, Ronda Curtin Engelhardt.

All were on the ice for a recent practice, with Engelhardt, 32, even joining her players for postgame sprints. But nothing in the arena acknowledges the Whitecaps’ leading scorer, Jonna Curtis, a left wing who was never a Golden Gopher, an Olympian or an All-American.

That the unheralded Curtis, 25, leads in the Whitecaps in goals (eight), assists (11) and points (19), rather than one of the team’s three Olympic gold medalists — wing Kendall Coyne Schofield is the third — illustrates the deep statewide talent pool. Minnesota was the first state to sanction girls high school hockey, in 1994. According to USA Hockey, more girls and women play hockey in Minnesota than any other state: close to 14,000 in 2017-18, the most recent season available.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
Mikael Backlund and Rasmus Andersson scored early in the third period Tuesday night for the Calgary Flames, who won their sixth consecutive game with a 3-1 victory over the New York Islanders at Nassau Coliseum.

Matthew Tkachuk opened the scoring for the Western Conference-leading Flames, who have won the first two games of an Eastern Conference road trip.

Flames goalie Mike Smith made 26 saves.

Josh Bailey scored for the Islanders, who lost for the third time in four games — a skid that began at Calgary last Wednesday — to fall into a tie for first place in the Metropolitan Division with the Washington Capitals.

Islanders goalie Robin Lehner recorded 24 saves.

After a scoreless first period, the Flames took the lead on a power-play goal by Tkachuk 2:57 into the second. Elias Lindholm, stationed in a face-off circle, fired a shot into the crease. Tkachuk, in one motion and despite being parallel to the net, managed to knock the puck down, regain control and tuck a shot through his legs and under Lehner’s legs.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
When Derick Brassard was traded from the Florida Panthers to the Colorado Avalanche on Monday, his transportation logistics were not too tricky. He just headed over to the other team’s locker room. The Panthers and the Avalanche faced off Monday night, and Brassard duly scored a goal for his new team.

In other offbeat N.H.L. trade-deadline news, Mikael Granlund was sent from the Minnesota Wild to the Nashville Predators on Monday while his partner was in labor.

When you think about it, a trade is a strange thing. Imagine showing up to work tomorrow and finding yourself sent to Albuquerque along with Bob from Accounting for some young coding prospects.

Given all the trades in all the sports over the years, it is not surprising that there have been some unusual ones.

Guys have been traded for one, two, three, four or even five other players. Players have been traded for just about anything but a bucket of balls. Oh, wait. Scratch that. Tim Fortugno, a minor league pitcher, was sent from the Reno Silver Sox to the Stockton Brewers in 1989 for $2,500 and some baseballs. “I told them to throw in 12 dozen balls and we had a deal,” Jack Patton, the Silver Sox general manager, told The Los Angeles Times.

Other legendary baseball swaps: Cy Young in 1890 for a new suit, and Ken Krahenbuhl in 1998 for catfish. Not Catfish Hunter, but 10 pounds of actual catfish.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
A year after publicly announcing their rebuilding effort in a letter to fans, the Rangers continued making moves on Monday at the N.H.L. trading deadline, stockpiling more young prospects and draft picks through two trades.

Two days after shipping the popular forward Mats Zuccarello to the Dallas Stars, the Rangers traded Kevin Hayes, a high-scoring forward, to the Winnipeg Jets and defenseman Adam McQuaid to the Columbus Blue Jackets.

In return for the 26-year-old Hayes, who, like McQuaid and Zuccarello, is set to become an unrestricted free agent after this season, the Rangers received the 22-year-old forward Brendan Lemieux — Winnipeg’s first-round pick in the June draft — and a conditional fourth-round pick in 2022.

The Rangers added two more draft picks in the trade with Columbus, as well as the 23-year-old prospect Julius Bergman, in exchange for McQuaid, 32.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
The London Knights doubled up the Sarnia Sting 4-2 on Sunday afternoon at the Progressive Auto Sales Arena in Sarnia.

Playing their third game in two and a half days, London willed themselves to stay with the Sting offensively early on and got 36 saves from overage goalie Joseph Raaymakers at the other end of the ice to earn their second straight victory and an important two points against a Western Conference opponent.

“It’s a character win for us,” said London assistant coach Dylan Hunter. “The first period wasn’t what we wanted, and the guys regrouped and came back and had a good second and third (period).”

Sarnia peppered the Knights net with 21 shots in the opening 20 minutes, but thanks to the work of Raaymakers in the crease, the score stayed tied at 2-2.

Hunter said Raaymakers was great.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
For Francis Paré getting the call from Hockey Canada to wear the maple leaf and help his country defend gold at the 2018 Olympics would be a dream come true.

“It would be an amazing honour. Just thinking about it gives me goosebumps,” Paré told Global News Wednesday.

The 29-year-old Quebec native is currently playing for Medvescak Zagreb in the Russia-based Kontinental Hockey League (KHL) and is one of several Canadians playing overseas who could be called upon to represent Canada at the 2018 Winter Games in Pyeongchang, South Korea after the NHL rejected the Olympics.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
The NHL announced Monday that it will not be sending its players to the 2018 Games in Pyeongchang, South Korea.

It will be the first time the NHL has not participated in the Winter Olympics since 1994.

READ MORE: NHL won’t participate in 2018 Olympics; League says matter ‘officially close ’

The NHL released a statement which essentially blamed its Players’ Association: “The NHLPA has now publicly confirmed that it has no interest or intention of engaging in any discussion that might make Olympic participation more attractive to the clubs.”

While the NHLPA has yet to respond, one player has already expressed his disappointment with the announcement.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
It appears the 2018 Winter Olympics will lack the star power of Sidney Crosby, Connor McDavid and Auston Matthews after the NHL announced Monday it will not interrupt next season to accommodate the Pyeongchang Games.

Instead, hockey will likely be represented on the global stage by many players with unrecognizable names – think Brad Schlegel, David Harlock and Dwayne Norris from Canada’s silver-medal winning team at the 1994 Lillehammer Games.
“Disappointing news @NHL won’t be part of the Olympics 2018,” New York Rangers goaltender and two-time Olympian Henrik Lundqvist said on Twitter. “A huge opportunity to market the game at the biggest stage is wasted.”

It was the hope of superstars like McDavid, Jonathan Toews and Alex Ovechkin that the NHL would come around to the big picture appeal of the 2018 Games, but the league never found the answer it was looking for.

What exactly might have swayed their opinion toward letting players attend isn’t clear. NHL owners never bought into the idea that shutting down the season for 17 days in February would benefit the league in the long run.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
Sidney Crosby was playing the best hockey of his life. Now his extraordinary year is on hold and no one is sure when he will be back on the ice.

Pittsburgh said Monday that its superstar centre has been diagnosed with at least his third concussion just a few days before the defending Stanley Cup champion Penguins open their season.
Crosby has been in dominant form, clearly the best player in hockey. He finished as a Hart Trophy finalist as league MVP, won the Conn Smythe Trophy as playoff MVP and led Team Canada to the World Cup title just a few months after winning his second Cup with the Penguins.

His short- and long-term future is in doubt after another concussion, an injury that has dogged him off and on over six years.

Coach Mike Sullivan told reporters that Crosby was concussed in practice Friday and that there was no timetable for his return. The diagnosis came as the Penguins prepare to raise their championship banner Thursday night before a home game against Alex Ovechkin and the Washington Capitals.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
"I felt great. I felt fresh," MacKinnon said, having played exactly 24 minutes in regulation time with another 2:26 in overtime. "That's why I take care of myself, so I can play in OT."

The winning goal was far from the greasy effort you usually expect when a playoff game goes beyond 60 minutes. Avalanche goalie Philipp Grubauer brilliantly turned aside Flames forward Michael Frolik at one end of the rink and Colorado took off in the other direction. Defenseman Ian Cole to forward Mikko Rantanen, who fed a speeding MacKinnon on left wing. The Colorado sniper made no mistake, rifling a 37-foot shot high past Calgary goalie Mike Smith's glove side that spoiled the party for a crowd of 19,289.

"It's just instinct," MacKinnon said of his shot selection. "I didn't really think. I think that's when everybody plays their best, being instinctual and going off how they feel and not really thinking too much or overthinking. I just put it where I wanted to."

This was a very different Avalanche team than the one that lost Game 1 to the Flames 4-0. 
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
Danton Heinen extended the lead to 3-0 at 10:39 of the second period following a turnover by Maple Leafs forward William Nylander at the left post.

Nazem Kadri cut the lead to 3-1 at 10:44 of the third period with a redirection in the high slot of Travis Dermott's slap shot from the left point.

"I didn't think we executed as well, weren't as crisp with the puck, and that didn't allow us to generate as much in the forecheck like we did in Game 1," Maple Leafs forward John Tavares said. "We knew they were going to come hard and respond and we just didn't execute at a high enough level. Sometimes that's the way it goes, and you just got to stay with it and find your game. We obviously got one to get back within two (goals), but unfortunately, we ran out of time. We just weren't as good today." 
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
NASHVILLE -- Craig Smith scored 5:00 into overtime to give the Nashville Predators a 2-1 win against the Dallas Stars in Game 2 of the Western Conference First Round at Bridgestone Arena on Saturday.

Smith scored off a bouncing puck inside the left face-off circle after a shot hit Stars defenseman Roman Polak.

"It was kind of a delayed reaction," Smith said. "I didn't see what it hit or how it went in or if it was in. Pretty exciting stuff. I've been on the bench watching overtime winners, but never have gotten one before, so it was awesome. It was cool."
The best-of-7 series is tied 1-1 with Game 3 at Dallas on Monday.

Ben Bishop made 40 saves for the Stars, who were 0-for-6 on the power play and outshot 42-23. 

"I think we needed to shoot a little bit more," Dallas forward Mats Zuccarello said. "Obviously I think we didn't play our best game today, but we're playing a really good team over there. If you would've asked me before the series if we would take a 1-1 series going home, I would take it. It's a good home team. We gave them two good games." 

Jamie Benn gave the Stars a 1-0 lead at 1:59 of the second period. Predators defenseman Mattias Ekholm turned over the puck in the defensive zone, and Tyler Seguin found Benn in the crease.

Rocco Grimaldi tied it 1-1 at 3:56 from the low slot off a pass from Austin Watson. Grimaldi replaced forward Brian Boyle (illness) in the Predators lineup after not playing Game 1 on Wednesday.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
About Last Night
Washington Capitals 4, Carolina Hurricanes 3 (OT): Brooks Orpik scored 1:48 into overtime to give the Capitals a 2-0 lead in the Eastern Conference First Round. It was Orpik's fourth goal in 151 NHL playoff games; three have been game-winners, including two in overtime. Carolina erased a 2-0 first-period deficit and a 3-2 deficit in the third period. Hurricanes goalie Petr Mrazek made 29 saves, including against John Carlson with one second remaining in the third period.

Nashville Predators 2, Dallas Stars 1 (OT): Craig Smith scored 5:00 into overtime to help the Predators even the best-of-7 series 1-1. Smith scored off a bouncing puck inside the left face-off circle after a shot hit Stars defenseman Roman Polak. Ben Bishop made 40 saves for the Stars, who were 0-for-6 on the power play and outshot 42-23. 

Boston Bruins 4, Toronto Maple Leafs 1: Tuukka Rask made 30 saves, and the Boston Bruins evened the best-of-7 series 1-1. Charlie Coyle, Brad Marchand, Danton Heinen and Patrice Bergeron scored for the Bruins. Nazem Kadri scored for the Maple Leafs and later received a major penalty and game misconduct for cross checking Bruins forward Jake DeBrusk with 5:57 left in the third period.

Colorado Avalanche 3, Calgary Flames 2 (OT): Nathan MacKinnon scored at 8:27 of overtime to help the Avalanche, the second wild card from the West, even the series 1-1. Calgary was 2:39 away from taking a 2-0 series lead, but Colorado's J.T. Compher scored to send it to overtime.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
WASHINGTON -- Brooks Orpik scored 1:48 into overtime to give the Washington Capitals a 4-3 win against the Carolina Hurricanes in Game 2 of the Eastern Conference First Round at Capital One Arena on Saturday.

Orpik received a pass from behind the net by Evgeny Kuznetsov and scored against Petr Mrazek from the left face-off circle.

It was Orpik's fourth goal in 151 NHL playoff games; three have been game-winners, including two in overtime.

"Kind of had them pinned in there," Orpik said. "[The] winger on my side didn't have [his] stick. I saw [Kuznetsov] had full possession, dove in there and he made a perfect pass.
Washington took a 2-0 lead in the best-of-7 series. Game 3 is at Carolina on Monday.

Nicklas Backstrom, T.J. Oshie and Tom Wilson scored for Washington, and Braden Holtby made 25 saves.

"The playoffs start, you try to go one shift at a time, one period at a time," Oshie said. "But maybe somewhere in the back of your mind you're hoping you can get away from the two home games with a 2-0 (lead). We were able to do that. It feels good."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
The New York Islanders, Columbus Blue Jackets and St. Louis Blues can each earn a big advantage in the 2019 Stanley Cup Playoffs on Sunday by taking 3-0 leads against the Pittsburgh Penguins, Tampa Bay Lightning and Winnipeg Jets, respectively.

Teams holding a 3-0 lead in a best-of-7 series are 186-4 (97.8 percent) all time.

The Islanders play Game 3 of the Eastern Conference First Round against the Penguins at PPG Paints Arena (12 p.m. ET; NBC, CBC, SN, TVAS) hoping to go ahead 3-0 in a best-of-7 series for the 10th time in their history and first since a four-game sweep of the Edmonton Oilers in the 1983 Stanley Cup Final. 

The Blue Jackets play Game 3 against the Lightning at Nationwide Arena (7 p.m. ET; NBCSN, SN360, TVAS, FS-O, SUN) and hope to join the 2012 Los Angeles Kings as the second team with a 3-0 lead in the first round against the Presidents' Trophy winner. The Kings defeated the Vancouver Canucks in five games en route to becoming the first No. 8 seed to win the Cup in the conference era (since 1974-75). 

The Lightning set a team record with 30 road wins this season, five more than the Blue Jackets, but are without Art Ross Trophy winner Nikita Kucherov (128 points), who is suspended one game for boarding Columbus defenseman Markus Nutivaara in Game 2.

The Blues will try to win the first three games of a best-of-7 series for the ninth time in their history and third in the past 20 years when they play the Jets in Game 3 of the Western Conference First Round at Enterprise Center (7:30 p.m. ET; CNBC, CBC, SN, TVAS2, FS-MW).
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
CALGARY -- Nathan MacKinnon scored 8:27 into overtime to give the Colorado Avalanche a 3-2 win against the Calgary Flames in Game 2 of the Western Conference First Round at Scotiabank Saddledome on Saturday.

MacKinnon scored on Mike Smith from the left face-off circle seconds after Avalanche goalie Philipp Grubauer made a save against Michael Frolik.

"The last 10 games (of the regular season) we had to tie up a lot of hockey games and we also blew some leads, we were in close games all season ... it's been a dogfight," MacKinnon said. "We feel good. We feel going back to Pepsi Center that we can hopefully win two games. Saying that, we have to take care of Game 3, but we feel good as a group."
The best-of-7 series is tied, with Game 3 at Colorado on Monday.

"A tough way to lose, but there's these moments all the time in playoffs and you've got to deal with them and move on," Calgary defenseman Mark Giordano said.

J.T. Compher and Matt Nieto scored, and Grubauer made 35 saves for the Avalanche.

"We've always had the confidence in this room and tonight shows it," Compher said. "Down late or running into a hot goalie, we know we can win games against this team. We're thrilled to be going back 1-1 and get back in front of that Pepsi Center crowd and try to get a lead in the series."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
Nazem Kadri has been offered an in-person hearing with the NHL Department of Player Safety.

The Toronto Maple Leafs forward is facing discipline for cross-checking Bruins forward Jake DeBrusk in third period of Game 2 of the Eastern Conference First Round on Saturday.

The incident occurred with 5:57 remaining in the Maple Leafs' 4-1 loss. Kadri received a major penalty for cross-checking and a game misconduct.

The best-of-7 playoff series is tied 1-1 with Game 3 at Toronto on Monday.

The following grounds are being considered for supplemental discipline: cross-checking. However, the Department of Player Safety retains the right to make adjustments to the infraction upon review.

The date and time of the hearing is to be determined. According to the NHL/NHLPA collective bargaining agreement, a player has the right to an in-person hearing if facing a disciplinary suspension of six or more games.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
Connor McDavid will not need surgery for a small PCL ligament tear in his left knee sustained in the Edmonton Oilers season finale, and is expected to recover in time for training camp next season.

"The Oilers medical staff, in collaboration with top orthopedic specialists, have determined a rehabilitation protocol for Connor McDavid, which will begin immediately," Edmonton said in a statement Friday.

X-rays of the center's left leg were negative; results of an MRI revealed the ligament tear.

"It seems to be fairly positive right now," McDavid said April 7, the day after he was injured. "I was just worried about standing up. I thought my leg was going to give way. To be completely honest, I thought my leg was in two pieces when I was sitting on the ice. Thankfully, the bone is OK, and thankfully I was able to get up and with a lot of help I was able to get off [the ice]."
McDavid was injured 3:42 into the second period of the game against the Calgary Flames. He was coming up the right wing when he was taken down by Flames defenseman Mark Giordano and collided with the goal post behind goalie Mike Smith.

"I've never had a lower-body injury before, it's something new for me," McDavid said. 
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
WINNIPEG -- The Winnipeg Jets might trail the St. Louis Blues in the Western Conference First Round, but themes of belief and determination were commonplace Saturday with the series shifting to St. Louis for Game 3.

The Jets lost 4-3 on Friday at home after a 2-1 loss there in Game 1. Winnipeg heads to St. Louis with the feeling that Game 3 on Sunday (7:30 p.m. ET; CNBC, CBC, SN, TVAS2, FS-MW) is a pivotal moment in the best-of-7 series.

"Obviously, it feels like tomorrow is a must-win game, but I don't think we need to reinvent the wheel here," Jets forward Andrew Copp said Saturday. "The team that handles the adversity, sticks together and pushes through is going to be the winner."
The Jets are taking some solace in the fact that each loss was by one goal, as well as from the fact that the Washington Capitals' road to the Stanley Cup last season started with a loss in each of their first two games.

"The Cup champs last year were in the same spot we're in right now," Copp said. "I don't think anyone's unpacking their locker or anything like that. There's a lot of belief. Two really tight games that could have gone either way. We're not in the spot we want to be, but we're not down and out yet."

Teams that win the first two games of a best-of-7 Stanley Cup Playoff series have a series record of 318-50 (86.4 percent); they are 241-30 (88.9 percent) when those wins come at home and 72-20 (78.3 percent) when they come on the road.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
1960: The Montreal Canadiens become the only team in NHL history to win the Stanley Cup five years in a row when they complete a four-game sweep in the Final with a 4-0 victory against the Toronto Maple Leafs at Maple Leaf Gardens. Jean Beliveau scores twice and Jacques Plante makes 30 saves for his 10th playoff shutout. The Canadiens win the Cup in the minimum eight games, having swept the Boston Bruins in the Semifinals.

In what turns out to be the final game of his NHL career, 39-year-old Maurice Richard has an assist on younger brother Henri Richard's second-period goal for his 126th and final Stanley Cup Playoff point. He retires before the next season and is inducted into the Hockey Hall of Fame in 1961 after the Hall waives the customary three-year waiting period.
928: The New York Rangers, playing their second season in the NHL, win the Stanley Cup with a 2-1 victory against the Montreal Maroons at the Forum in the deciding game of the best-of-5 Final. Center Frank Boucher scores twice for the Rangers, who have to play all five games on the road because Madison Square Garden is not available. New York overcomes a 2-1 series deficit by winning Games 4 and 5 to become the second U.S.-based team (along with the 1917 Seattle Metropolitans of the Pacific Coast Hockey Association) to win the Cup.

 

1942: The Toronto Maple Leafs tie a Stanley Cup Final single-game record for goals by defeating the Detroit Red Wings 9-3 in Game 5 at Maple Leaf Gardens. Forward Don Metz, inserted into the lineup after Toronto loses the first three games, scores three goals and finishes with five points. Center Syl Apps scores two goals and sets up three others. Toronto blows the game open with five unanswered goals in the second period.

</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
BUFFALO -- Cayden Primeau got his first taste of life as a professional hockey player. Now he's ready for more.

After signing a three-year, entry-level contract on March 31 with the Montreal Canadiens, who selected him in the seventh round (No. 199) of the 2017 NHL Draft, Primeau spent a week with the Laval Rocket of the American Hockey League on a professional tryout contract.

"It was good to get in there and see what it's all about," the 19-year-old said after capping his college career Friday by winning the Mike Richter Award, which honors the most outstanding goalie in NCAA Division I hockey. "I didn't play but I was able to practice with the guys a couple of times. [It was good] just being able to experience that level and what it's like to be in that kind of environment."

Primeau was 25-10-1 with a 2.09 goals-against average and .933 save percentage in his sophomore season at Northeastern. The save percentage is the best in school history, and the GAA was only slightly higher than the school-record 1.92 he had as a freshman. Primeau helped Northeastern tie for second place in Hockey East and qualify for the NCAA Tournament for the second straight year. He was named MVP of the Beanpot and the Hockey East tournaments.

He's quickly risen up Montreal's depth chart. in goal and next season, he'll embark on his professional hockey career with a chance to learn from Carey Price, who became the Canadiens' all-time leader in wins (315) on March 12.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
TAMPA, Fla. -- Alexandre Texier's friends back home in Grenoble, France all want to know the same thing.

"They just love the big stars here in the NHL, so they always talk about [Artemi] Panarin," said Texier, the Columbus Blue Jackets rookie forward. "They ask me if he's good or not."

Panarin, the Blue Jackets big star, is what they know about Texier's life now. The rest of it, a 19-year-old living in North America, an NHLer for eight days and already a veteran of two Stanley Cup Playoff games, both wins, they really have no clue what that is like.
In many ways, Texier has no clue either, and that's the beauty of him right now.

Everything is happening so fast for Texier that he hasn't had time yet to take stock, to fully comprehend the fact that he's living his dream six months before his 20th birthday (Sept. 13) and that his team is up stunningly up 2-0 on the Presidents' Trophy-winning Tampa Bay Lightning in the best-of-7 Eastern Conference First Round.

Game 3 will be played at Nationwide Arena on Sunday (7 p.m. ET; NBCSN, SUN, FS-O, SN360, TVAS).

"Just play hockey, have fun, you know," Texier said. "Nobody knows me in this league, so that's pretty good for me. I just want to play."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
"I thought we had a good first half of the first, but then tough in the second half," Fleury said, "but in the second and third [periods] I thought we played really solid."

He finished with 34 saves on the way to his 76th victory in the Stanley Cup Playoffs, one from tying Mike Vernon for seventh place on the NHL's all-time list. He improved to 35-21 in playoff games following a loss.

Though the Sharks pulled goalie Martin Jones and replaced him with Aaron Dell at 6:39 of the first period, Vegas coach Gerard Gallant remained confident in Fleury, even after he allowed goals by San Jose centers Logan Couture, Tomas Hertl and Joe Thornton to tie the game.

"I thought they could have had five goals in the first," Gallant said. "A few of the saves he made in the first were unbelievable. They scored those three late, but he didn't have a chance on any of those. He made some great saves, and he was real key for our win tonight."

The road to tie the series wasn't an easy one for Fleury; the Sharks had eight power-play opportunities and converted one.

Vegas scored two shorthanded goals, by defenseman Colin Miller and center William Karlsson. The Golden Knights also blocked 26 shots.

"It's big, especially with a team like that," Fleury said of the blocked shots. "They shoot the puck, always have traffic in front of the net. If you block some, there's no chaos, there's no rebound … it just ends the play quicker."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
The Sharks appeared to take a 4-3 lead 51 seconds into the second period, but the goal was nullified for goaltender interference on Couture, who was given a two-minute penalty.

"I didn't have much of a view," Fleury said. "I was looking at the puck and couldn't look to my right. The ref made the right call."

Couture did not agree.

"I haven't seen the replay yet but I thought I was outside of the crease," Couture said. "I thought Fleury kind of ran into me, but I'll have to look at it. Tough way to lose."

Stone scored on the ensuing power play at 1:31 to give Vegas a 4-3 lead.

Karlsson scored shorthanded at 7:35 of the third period for the 5-3 final.

Eakin gave the Golden Knights a 1-0 lead 58 seconds into the first period. Miller scored shorthanded at 4:37 to make it 2-0, and Pacioretty extended the lead to 3-0 at 6:11.

"We were down 3-0 [6:11] in," Sharks coach Peter DeBoer said of pulling Jones. "I didn't put it on [Jones]. We needed a shot in the arm to change our momentum."

San Jose scored three goals in 2:09 to tie it. Couture scored 4-on-4 at 16:59 to make it 3-1, Hertl scored a power-play goal 39 seconds later to make it 3-2 at 17:38, and Thornton tied it 3-3 at 19:08.

"I don't think the intermission could've come at a better time,"said Stone, whose three goals lead the NHL. "To be able to get in the locker room, control our emotions a little bit, get out there and get back to what we do, no matter how you get there, the game is still tied in the first period on the road. Yeah, we gave up a three-goal lead, but we're still in a good spot."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
The Penguins have shown their resilience this season, finishing third in the Metropolitan Division after starting 7-8-4, and Crosby said he doesn't believe they need to change their approach.

"The urgency becomes higher and that should bring out the best in us," Crosby said. "We've been in these situations this year and it's brought out the best in our team, so I think if we come out with the right mentality and execute a little better, we'll get the result we want."

Crosby, who had 100 points (35 goals, 65 assists) in 79 regular-season games, does not have a point in the series. He has three shots on goal and is minus-1.

"These games are tight and close-checking, and when it's that kind of game, you have to execute. So I think that when it's 1-1 or 2-2, as it's been these last couple of games, we have got to get that next one," Crosby said. "We haven't been able to do that, and that's the difference to me. Other than that, I'd say the chances are pretty even."

Sullivan said he believes it's just a matter of time before Crosby finds his game.

"I haven't been disappointed," Sullivan said. "[Crosby] is too good and too important to our team. I would never be disappointed in him. I know how hard he competes, how much he cares."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>hockey</SPORT>
<BODY>
UNIONDALE, N.Y. -- Barry Trotz implored the New York Islanders fans to be even louder for Game 2 of the Eastern Conference First Round against the Pittsburgh Penguins at Nassau Coliseum on Friday.

And with their help, the Islanders are halfway to advancing to the next round of the Stanley Cup Playoffs after a 3-1 win.

The best-of-7 series moves to PPG Paints Arena in Pittsburgh for Game 3 on Sunday (noon ET; NBC, CBC, SN, TVAS), where Penguins fans will attempt to match those decibel levels.
"They were good; they get an A-plus from me tonight," Trotz said of the fans, many of whom stayed after the final buzzer. "They were outstanding. Keep it up. I can hear you right now. Fantastic. That's what playoffs are about. That's what I remember about this building; it's a hard place to come in, the fans are fabulous, they're passionate and pushing you along."

They did everything they could to push the Islanders along seven minutes into the third period, when they were shown a video of the penalty-shot goal Shawn Bates scored in Game 4 against the Toronto Maple Leafs in a first-round series 17 years earlier.

Bates was in the building Friday, waving an orange towel seconds after they showed his goal on the scoreboard.

The Islanders got a pretty good idea of what the building felt like in 2002 when Jordan Eberle's second goal of the series gave New York a 2-1 lead with 12:06 remaining in the third period.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
OAKLAND, Calif. -- On the first day of the NBA playoffs, a familiar sound was heard, a warning actually, and it was tim-ber! Heavily-favored and highly seeded teams falling in unlikely places, and then the Golden State Warriors began defense of their back-to-back championships, and you know what dropped to the floor?

In order: Stephen Curry right on his wallet after swishing a long distance 3-pointer that shook the building; Patrick Beverley after colliding with and then having to hear about it from a trash-talking Kevin Durant; and finally, any faint hopes the Clippers might have had to make this first-round series even remotely interesting.

Yes, while madness reigned in other playoff cities, Oakland enjoyed a ray of reality.

 Warriors-Clippers series hub
Warriors vs. Clippers could very well be the lone mismatch in these playoffs because simple arithmetic says so. Five stars for the Warriors going against zero stars for the Clippers equals a four-game sweep, or at least it seems. At 121-104 Warriors, Game 1 was pretty much a wash, with the only drama being the game within the game.

Specifically: Pat Bev being Pat Bev.

Beverley is the NBA's resident porcupine, bringing a prickly exterior designed to rub folks the wrong way. His purpose is to disrupt with defense, and he is among the league's best at that, and also with chatter, which he uses to get under more skin than a tattoo.

Clippers coach Doc Rivers made the curious if gutsy decision to use Beverley at times as a second layer of defense against Durant. That's a salute to Beverley; although the guard gives away seven inches to Durant, he works hard to minimize that disadvantage but mostly, the Clippers have no one better to offer on the double team.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Kevin Durant was recently asked if being a member of the Golden State Warriors has been all that he thought it would when he signed with the franchise in 2016.

“Of course,” Durant said.

Durant and the Warriors are attempting to win their third straight title this season.

“I came here knowing for a fact, that every media member, every fan was going to call me every name in the book for however long I was here and I was going to take the brunt of everything. I knew coming here,” Durant said. “But I wanted to be a part of this so bad, I didn’t give a f---. Same with LeBron (James). He took all of that heat, no matter what.”

Durant has been forced to improve as a player and a teammate within Golden State's system.

“I enjoy the way they played basketball. I never played with shooters like that. That moved. That were versatile players. I wanted to be a part of that,” Durant said. “My game was talking to me. Not that other s---. The spirit of the game was talking to me. Not the spotlight or the fame that comes from being the best player. Not the legacy. I swear on my life, that don’t mean nothing to me. How I build myself up in this NBA life, it doesn’t mean anything to me. I just want to play great basketball every second I’m on the court, and that was a perfect opportunity for me to do so.”
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Duke had a higher rating for their 26 games on ESPN this season than the network's 101 telecasts for the NBA.

Duke averaged 2.23 million viewers per telecast compared to 1.99 million for the NBA.

The statistics were featured in a Tweet by the Duke basketball program with an image of Zion Williamson attached and the hashtag #TheDukeEffect.

Williamson is expected to be the No. 1 overall pick in the draft and became one of college basketball's most celebrated players in several years.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The Los Angeles Lakers have been granted permission by the Philadelphia 76ers to interview Monty Williams for their vacant head-coach opening.

Rob Pelinka will either speak to Williams by phone or travel to meet with him in person during the 76ers playoff series against the Nets.

Pelinka has reportedly honed in on Williams or Tyronn Lue as the next Lakers coach.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Steve Kerr said that Kevin Durant has to be wary of getting a 1-game suspension after getting ejected with two technical fouls following a confrontation with Patrick Beverly.

"We took the bait. [Durant] took the bait, and that's two technicals. You get seven technicals, your seventh one is a suspension in the playoffs. Whether you play four playoff games or 24, seven is the magic number. So he's got four to play with after one game," said Kerr.

Durant and Beverly were ejected late in the fourth quarter after they both received their second technical foul for exchanging words.

Durant described his matchup with Beverly as "fun."

"He's a Chicago kid, man -- grew up and raised in the Chicago area, so those dudes played with a different type of grit, so I can appreciate that about Pat. And we know what he's gonna bring to the table -- just physicality, mucking up the game a little bit with his physicality, his talking, just everything -- that's what he brings to each team he plays on. That's his identity, and they support him with the Clippers. So for me, I know that coming into the series, so I thought it was fun tonight," added Durant.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Adam Silver said the NBA will evaluate whether a shorter season will improve their product.

Over the past few days, many playoff teams have strategically rested players either for actual rest or in an attempt to manipulate the seeding of the playoffs.

“I'm never quite comfortable where things are at,” said Silver.

“I think especially over that last week, you can imagine there's a fair amount of angst in the league office.”

Teams had been “calling our general counsel Rick Buchanan or calling Mark Tatum or calling me.”

Said Silver: “There aren't always bright-line answers we can give them. We always have one eye, too, that we know that the playoffs are what this is all about. So we don't want to end up forcing a team to do something silly when it could cause issues in terms of health for the most important part of the season.”

The NBA could shorten the season or have an in-season tournament similar to soccer.

“Those are all things we're looking at,” Silver said. “They're not the kinds of format changes you're going to make without lots and lots of deliberation."

The NBA would be unlikely to implement any changes for another five or six years.

“Sometimes it's science, but sometimes it's art,” Silver said. “I think a fair point from fans could be if ultimately the science suggests that 82 games is too many games for these players, maybe you shouldn't have an 82-game season. I accept that, and that's something we'll continue to look at.”
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Nikola Mirotic is expected to return to the Milwaukee Bucks for game 1 tomorrow against the Detroit Pistons.

Mirotic has been out for the last month with a fractured thumb.

"Not much soreness, as we expected. I should be ready to go," said Mirotic.

Mirotic added that he was hungry for playoff basketball.

"This is going to be my fourth playoffs in five years. The guys are ready, but the message from our coach is that there's nothing different in the playoffs. We need to play our same basketball. Play hard. I think we should be fine. We are a very deep team and very hungry."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Entering Milwaukee's playoff opener against Detroit on Sunday, there are four main questions surrounding the Bucks in terms of their championship viablity. One, at what point, if at all, will Giannis Antetokounmpo's fledgling, if improving, outside shot become too big an obstacle to work around? Two, can the league's No. 1 regular-season defense remain elite in the playoffs while continuing to give up such a high volume of 3-pointers? Three, given the Bucks' reliance on multiple floor spacers and versatile defenders, to what degree will the Malcolm Brogdon and Nikola Mirotic injuries cripple them, particularly in the early rounds? And four, how big a deal will their collective lack of deep playoff experience be? 

To that last question, it didn't hurt the 2015 Warriors, and there are a ton of similarities between that Golden State team and this Milwaukee squad. But we'll get to that in a bit. 

For now, In fairness, it seems unnecessarily pessimistic to address the "concerns" of an obviously fantastic basketball team before touching on its many virtues -- the main one of which, of course, is the simple fact that the Bucks have one of the best players, if not the best player, on the planet in Antetokounmpo, and they have married the perfect system with a perfectly suited supporting cast to fully maximize his otherworldly attributes. For one Eastern Conference scout, that's as far as the conversation needs to go.

"[The Bucks] are just so balanced, offensively and defensively," the scout told CBS Sports. "They create so many driving lanes with their spacing, and they have the best driver of the basketball in the league. It's a pretty simple formula, really. And with a player like Giannis, I don't see any reason why it would just stop working in the playoffs." 

To be clear: That doesn't mean this particular scout thinks Milwaukee is the clear favorite to come out of the East. It just means that if the Bucks don't come out of the East, or even if they, say, lose a second-round series to Boston, it wouldn't be about Milwaukee's so-called shortcomings as much as it would be about one of the other highly capable Eastern teams doing what they do a little bit better. Indeed, the margin between the East's top four teams is virtually indistinguishable to the naked eye. 

"I was literally having this conversation the other night with some other scouts, just asking each other, like, 'who do you see coming out of the East?' There were three or four different answers. I mean, nobody really knows," the scout told CBS. "I think it's all going to come down to matchups. Who's healthy? Who hits a few big shots? It could be something very small that tips a series."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
It's another thing entirely to step back when you're in the middle of that greatness and pause for a moment, breathe it all in, and recognize that no great things last forever.

This is where we stand with the Golden State Warriors. Saturday's dominant win in Game 1 of their first-round series against the Los Angeles Clippers could very well mark the beginning of the end of one of the greatest dynasties in modern American sports.

It's easy to look at Saturday night's game as another ho-hum display of Warriors' dominance over all comers: Steph Curry being Steph Curry, scoring 38 electric points while setting the all-time record for playoffs 3s in a career, and Draymond Green jawing with the refs about a missed foul call just minutes into the game and keeping up that intensity throughout, and Kevin Durant dropping a quiet 23 points before getting kicked out of the game in the fourth quarter after an altercation with Patrick Beverley. Hey, they're the Warriors. We've come to expect these 121-104 Warriors wins when you feel like they weren't even at their best. Forget all the drama of this season: It's playoff time, and the Warriors have flipped their playoff switch. Frankly, it'll be easy to look at all these Warriors games with that same ho-hum feel until they (possibly/probably/likely/inevitably, depending on your view on destiny) hoist the Larry O'Brien Trophy for the fourth time in five years. After all, we've seen this before. We've seen it so much that we've become inured to Steph Curry draining impossible 35-footers, or Kevin Durant showing us why he may have surpassed LeBron as the greatest basketball player on earth, or Klay Thompson being the most low-key, low-maintenance two-way force the NBA has ever seen, or Draymond Green playing the antihero despite playing basketball the exact way that your high school coach wants his guys to play basketball.

Do not do that.

Do not take these Warriors for granted.

Because we really may be staring at the beginning of the end of this dynasty.

There's more than a pretty good chance that everything will look different for the Warriors next year. First is the sparkling new arena: No longer in gritty Oakland but instead in that opulent tech-centered city on the other side of the bay.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
OAKLAND, Calif. -- We really should be ashamed of ourselves ... all of us.

Stephen Curry opened the Golden State Warriors' quest for a three-peat by putting up 38 points and 15 rebounds while making 8 of 12 3-pointers, breaking Ray Allen's all-time postseason record for threes in the process, and all we wanted to talk about was Kevin Durant and Patrick Beverley's pseudo-trash talk that led to double ejections.

It makes sense, presumably, because that was something new, something fresh. Curry going ballistic, becoming literally unguardable for long stretches of his team's most important games -- yawn. Seen it before.

"I'm never surprised when it comes to anything with Steph shooting the basketball," Draymond Green said after Golden State's 121-104 Game 1 win over the Clippers. "I don't think there's much argument when anyone says he's the greatest shooter of all time. I don't know if you can find many people to argue that ... It don't shock me."

Green was far from the only one to act like Curry's exploits were commonplace. 

"I mean, well, I expect it at this point," Kevin Durant said. "I'm not surprised by anything he does. You know, I expect him to come in and shoot well every night because he puts the work in."

Wait a second, now we expect a guy to hit eight of his first 10 threes against playoff-level defense? We expect a guy to hit a heat-check three from 30 feet while falling to the floor? The world's best pole vaulter couldn't even clear a bar that high.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The Denver Nuggets and San Antonio Spurs face off in a test of how much playoff experience actually matters. The Nuggets haven't made the playoffs since 2013, and have very little playoff experience on their team. The Spurs haven't missed the playoffs since seemingly the Roosevelt administration, and they have a man named Gregg Popovich. But then there's the question of home-court advantage: The Nuggets have it, and they also had the best home record in the NBA this season. (The Spurs' home record was tied for third.)

Portland Trail Blazers vs. the Oklahoma City Thunder? We got two teams that both lost, in somewhat embarrassing fashion, in the first round last year. We also got two teams that are dealing with different levels of injuries. For the Blazers, Jusuf Nurkic's broken leg a few weeks ago was an absolute gut punch; now they have to rely on Enes Kanter. For the Thunder, how will Paul George's shoulder hold up? He hasn't been the same MVP-caliber player since the All-Star break.

And then there's the rematch from a year ago: The fourth-seeded Houston Rockets against the fifth-seeded Utah Jazz. The Rockets won in a five-game series, but that series was a lot closer than those five games would make it seem -- especially when you consider how banged-up the Jazz were by the end of it. The Jazz are a little bit better than a year ago, the Rockets are little bit worse. If there's one first-round series with the potential to go the full seven games, well, this one's it.

The playoffs always bring surprises. But our NBA staff is going to do our best to predict how this first round will go.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Process to obtain two star players who will be unrestricted free agents at the end of this season.

The mentality was to go deep in the playoffs this season and make Philly an even more attractive place to be next season: For Butler, or for Harris, for both, or maybe for others.

Now let's not overreact to the 76ers dropping the first game of the NBA playoffs on Saturday to the deep, balanced, impressive Brooklyn Nets. This is not a five-alarm fire for the 76ers -- not yet. The 76ers still have the four most talented players on the floor in this series. They still have a starting five in Embiid, Butler, Harris, Simmons and J.J. Redick that has statistically been one of the NBA's best this season despite limited minutes together.

But Saturday's loss illustrated exactly how small a margin of error the Sixers have.

And if you're going to pick a loss to overreact to, well, Saturday's performances by every 76er except Butler gives you plenty of material to work with.

The single most important thing for the Sixers is, on Saturday and on any day, the health of Embiid. The day before the game, Embiid was downgraded to doubtful because of pain in his knee when he jumped and when he landed, and he told reporters that he had "no idea" whether he'd play in Game 1. It wasn't announced until minutes before the game on Saturday that he would in fact play. One of the problems with the Sixers is that they couldn't afford to rest Embiid on Saturday; they're more than 11 points per 100 possessions better when Embiid is on the floor, and his replacements – Boban Marjanovic, Jonah Bolden, Amir Johnson – are all major drop-offs.

So Embiid did play, and he looked like a guy who probably shouldn't have. He was slow getting down the court. In the first half he launched 3-pointers -- missing all five of them -- instead of being aggressive. He finished with 22 points and 15 rebounds, but those aren't the key numbers. The key numbers are that Embiid only played 24 minutes, and in those 24 minutes, the 76ers were outscored by 17 points.

But the Sixers could have weathered a rough game from their star. If only the rest of the team had shown up. Simmons in particular was terrible, with his lack of outside shooting again limiting his game. He scored nine points on only nine shots, and he missed four of his five free throws. Simmons had a team-worst plus-minus of -21, a mark that was equaled by Redick. Redick had another rough playoff appearance -- he's a 41.3 percent career 3-point shooter in the regular season but a 36.3 percent 3-point shooter in the playoffs -- scoring only five points before fouling out. And you could be forgiven on Saturday if you forgot Harris even played for the Sixers, as he was nearly invisible, putting up only seven shots (in 41 minutes) and scoring only four points. The Nets were up 17 points in their first half despite Butler locking down D'Angelo Russell for the first 24 minutes of the game.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Sunday's first-round NBA postseason slate features four matchups. With plenty of player prop bets to wager on, we dive into some of the most intriguing options.

Kyrie Irving Over/Under 24.5 points
The Indiana Pacers lack star power without the injured Victor Oladipo, so they'll need a collective effort if they want to bounce the Boston Celtics. That all starts on the defensive side of the ball, where the Pacers led the NBA in points allowed per game this season, surrendering just 104.7. If they want any shot at a first-round upset, they'll have to contain Irving, the Celtics' leading scorer at 23.8 points per game.

Irving's scoring numbers have been a mixed bag against Indiana this year, putting up point totals of 17, 30, 15, and 12 in the team's four meetings.

Overall, the Pacers allow the least amount of points to opposing point guards at just 19.6 per game.

Andre Drummond Over/Under 34.5 points + rebounds + assists
Drummond puts up double-doubles at a torrid pace, finishing the regular season averaging 17.3 points and 15.6 rebounds per game. The Bucks rank No. 1 in defensive efficiency but do have some weaknesses in the post, allowing 25.8 points and 14.1 rebounds to opposing centers this year. Drummond stuffed the stat sheet with 20 points, 13 boards, and four assists during the Pistons' Jan. 29 meeting against the Bucks, but failed to surpass a combined 25 points, rebounds, and assists in their other three matchups.

P.J. Tucker Over/Under 6.5 points
The Utah Jazz did a great job of defending the Houston Rockets during the regular season, holding them to under 41 percent shooting in three of their four meetings. Tucker averaged just 7.3 points per game during the year and gets the short end of the stick based on the matchup.

Utah's one of the league's best at guarding forwards, and they held Tucker to six points or fewer in three of their games, including a scoreless output.

Russell Westbrook Over/Under 46.5 points + rebounds + assists
The Oklahoma City Thunder had the Portland Trail Blazers' number this season with four wins and Westbrook was at the forefront of it. He was responsible for a 37-point effort, two separate triple-doubles, and a 31-point, seven-assist, nine-rebound output.

Portland has struggled against opposing floor generals all season long. The Trail Blazers allowed 24.6 points per game, the sixth-most in the NBA. With a game expected to finish in the 220s, Westbrook should be in for another fun night on the stat sheet.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
DENVER (AP) DeMar DeRozan scored 18 points and Derrick White had a key steal in the closing seconds in the San Antonio Spurs' 101-96 victory over the Denver Nuggets on Saturday night in Game 1 of their playoff series.

White stole the ball at midcourt from Jamal Murray with 1.3 seconds left after LaMarcus Aldridge sank a pair of free throws following his key defensive rebound of Murray's errant shot that would have given the Nuggets a 98-97 lead with seven seconds left.

Game 2 is Tuesday night in Denver, where the second-seeded Nuggets failed to parlay the NBA's best home-court record (34-7) into a win against the seventh-seeded but much more seasoned Spurs.

San Antonio is making its 22nd straight playoff appearance, this one with a new cast that includes DeRozan, who came over from Toronto in the Kawhi Leonard trade.

The Spurs' win marked the third by a road team on the opening day of the NBA playoffs. They joined the Nets, who won at Philadelphia, and Magic, who won at Toronto.

The Nuggets, making their first playoff appearance in six years, trailed most of the night. Their last lead came with four minutes left in the first quarter but they trimmed a 12-point deficit to one in the closing minutes.

They had the ball with 13 seconds left trailing 97-96 but Murray's shot was off - as it was all night - and Aldridge, who shot just 6 of 19 himself, corralled the rebound, then sank two free throws to make it 99-96 with 6.9 seconds remaining.

The Nuggets were hoping for a game-tying 3 although they were just 6 of 28 from long range.

They never got the chance, though, as White stripped Murray and drew the foul, then sank both shots.

Denver All-Star Nikola Jokic posted the fourth triple-double in Nuggets playoff history, with 10 points, 14 assists and 14 rebounds. But he was hesitant on offense all night, taking just nine shots and making four of them.

Throttled by Aldridge, Jokic passed up opportunity after opportunity and shot an airball on a 3-pointer at a crucial moment in the second half that helped San Antonio hold off Denver's surge.

White added 16 points for San Antonio and Aldridge and Bryn Forbes each had 15. Reserve Rudy Gay scored 14.

Gary Harris led Denver with 20 points and Murray had 17, but that was on 8-of-24 shooting, including 0 for 6 from the arc.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
DENVER (AP) -- Nikola Jokic overcame suffocating double teams to become the fourth player in NBA history to record a triple-double in his playoff debut and the first since LeBron James in 2006.

What did it mean to him?

"To be honest, nothing," Jokic said.

It also mattered little to the San Antonio Spurs, who beat the Denver Nuggets 101-96 in Game 1 of their Western Conference playoff series Saturday night.

Jokic's accomplishment was rendered a footnote by LaMarcus Aldridge's suffocating defense, DeMar DeRozen's 18 points, Derrick White's clinching steal in the closing seconds and all those wide-open shots that just didn't fall for Denver.

BOX SCORE: SPURS 101, NUGGETS 96

Although Jokic pulled down 14 rebounds and dished out 14 assists, he took just nine shots, made four, and was limited to 10 points, less than half his regular season scoring average of 20.1.

Spurs coach Gregg Popovich called it a wash because Aldridge wasn't himself, either, going just 6 of 19 for 15 points.

"We didn't let Jokic play as he wanted and they didn't let LaMarcus play as much as he wanted," Popovich said. "It is important because they are both great players and they are going to continue to get a lot of attention throughout the series."

Aldridge said this is what everyone can expect this whole series, too.

"Both bigs kind of never really got comfortable down there. When you have two bigs that are so big for your team, it's going to be like that," Aldridge said. "We did a good job of just trying to mix it up on him. They did the same thing on me."

Nuggets coach Michael Malone said he didn't wish his All-Star had taken more shots.

"Every time he put it down, there was somebody right there. They trapped him every time," Malone said. "So, I think Nikola has a high IQ. He's going to make the right play. Unfortunately, we didn't make them pay for double-teaming enough."

The Nuggets made just 42 percent of their shots, 21 percent from 3-point range, and missed eight free throws while failing to score a single fast-break basket.

"I think if we're making shots, it becomes a lot harder to double-team him consistently," Malone said. "They stayed with it because we couldn't make a shot. So, that was the tough thing about it. But I love Nikola's approach. I love his play-making. I love his passing."

The sellout crowd at the Pepsi Center, where the Nuggets went 34-7 for the best home record in the league, certainly wanted Jokic to take more shots. But even those calls quieted after Jokic shot an airball on a 3 at a crucial point in the fourth quarter.

White stole the ball at midcourt from Jamal Murray with 1.3 seconds left after Aldridge sank a pair of free throws following his key defensive rebound of Murray's errant shot that would have given the Nuggets the lead with seven seconds left.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
he Golden State Warriors cruised to a 121-104 win against the Los Angeles Clippers on Saturday night at Oracle Arena, taking the early lead in their opening-round playoff series.

It was a feud between Warriors star Kevin Durant and Clippers point guard Patrick Beverley that stole the show, however.

RELATED: Warriors win

Durant and Beverley, after feuding back and forth throughout the contest, were ejected late in the fourth quarter of the matchup.

Beverley, while bringing the ball up the court with less than five minutes to go in the game, lost control of the ball near the half-court line when confronted by Durant.

Durant then forced Beverley out of bounds, which gave the Warriors possession. However Durant stood over Beverley once the call was made and clearly said something, which made Beverly jump up and get into his face.

Quickly, an official jumped in the middle and gave both players a technical foul before ejecting them from the game.

Durant, though, didn’t seem bothered by the ejection, and was seen smiling, clapping and high-fiving with fans on his way out of the arena.

The two had been going at it throughout the contest, and can be seen having a lengthy conversation after Beverley fouled Durant from behind while he was attempting to go up for a layup just before the ejection.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
TORONTO (AP) -- For the Orlando Magic, the first game of the playoffs felt a lot like the final few weeks of the regular season: high stakes, small margins, and a big win at the end of the day.

D.J. Augustin scored 25 points, including the tiebreaking 3-pointer with 3.5 seconds left, and the Magic beat the Toronto Raptors 104-101 in Game 1 of their Eastern Conference first-round series on Saturday.

BOX SCORE:  MAGIC 104, RAPTORS 101 

Kawhi Leonard got a final shot for Toronto, but missed the rim with his 3-pointer from the top.

Orlando went 22-9 over the final 31 games of the season to clinch its first playoff berth since 2012.

"I think it helps," Magic coach Steve Clifford said of his team's tough regular-season finish. "We've been playing games that we had to win and were meaningful games for a while."

Nikola Vucevic, who scored 11 points, said Orlando's stretch drive help the team's mental preparation for the grind of the postseason.

"Throughout this last month, we were able to fight through a lot of different adversity and it has kind of prepared us for the playoffs," Vucevic said.

And, when crunch time arrived in Game 1, Orlando was entirely unfazed.

"We made a bunch of big plays in the last three or four minutes," Clifford said.

Aaron Gordon had 10 points and 10 rebounds, Evan Fournier scored 16 points and Jonathan Isaac had 11 as the No. 7-seeded Magic became the latest team to beat Toronto in the opening game of a playoff series. The Raptors are 2-14 in playoff openers.

"We know who we are and this is one game," Toronto's Kyle Lowry said. "We've got to make sure we know who we are and execute what we can do. When we do what we are supposed to do, we are really, really good."

Leonard scored 25 points, Pascal Siakam had 24 and Fred VanVleet had 14 for the second-seeded Raptors, who reclaimed the lead after trailing by 16 points in the second quarter, but couldn't hold on down the stretch.

Toronto got 13 points apiece from Danny Green and Marc Gasol, but Lowry finished scoreless, missing all seven of his attempts. Lowry did have eight assists and seven rebounds.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
It took Luke Walton just over 24 hours to land on his feet with another head coaching job in the NBA. And he gets to coach a team that had a better record while not even leaving California.

ESPN's Adrian Wojnarowski broke the news that Luke Walton was closing in on a deal to join the Kings. Only a few minutes later, The Athletic's Sam Amick added that the deal with Walton and the Kings has been agreed to. Walton will be under contract through the 2022-23 season.
Vlade Divac has reportedly had his eye on Walton for a few years now. Walton is back in the league and is doing with a very talented team rich in high lottery talent piled up over the past few years. Also, in what will likely be a refreshing twist for Walton, he will have a better opportunity to mold the team into his vision than he did in his one year with LeBron James.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The Boston Celtics have turned the corner so many times this season they’ve walked around the block over and over again.

What the Celtics deliver in the playoffs remains a guess. It could be a first-round exit against Indiana. It could be an NBA finalist. The fourth-seeded Celtics (49-33) showed this season that both scenarios are plausible.

There’s the team that went 14-4 just after the new year, and there’s the team that went 8-11 in late February through late March.

There are wins over Golden State, Philadelphia and Toronto and losses to Chicago, Phoenix and New York. There have been awkward team moments (Kyrie Irving publicly calling out his younger teammates) and special team bonding moments (a long coast-to-coast flight filled with card games and laughter).

“It takes time to come together as a team and seeing how good you can be,” coach Brad Stevens told reporters this week. “We’ve had our moments. I’m not sure we’ve peaked, which I guess is a good thing. But we’re going to have to play awfully well and awfully hard, awfully smart, and awfully together if we’re going to have a chance to win any game, let alone any series.”

Here's the thing, the Celtics know how to play well, hard, smart and together. They’ve done it together, they’ve done it when they’ve been on other teams and done it when players are out with injury.

Irving is a champion. Al Horford has played in the conference finals multiple times. Jayson Tatum and Jaylen Brown played in the conference finals last season with Irving.

With no LeBron James in anyone’s way in the East, the conference is as wide open as it gets. Five teams – Milwaukee, Toronto, Philadelphia, Indiana and Boston – are capable of playing in the conference finals, and the Celtics are the rare four seed that could reach the finals and it wouldn’t be a surprise.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
A preseason encounter with Kobe Bryant helped Draymond Green prepare for the end of the Warriors’ dynasty whenever it occurs, writes Nick Friedell of ESPN. Green had expected Bryant to be missing the game when they talked, but the former Lakers star was at peace with retirement and has moved on to the next chapter of his life.

“[Kobe is] not sitting in retirement like, ‘Man, I wish I can go be out there.’ No, he’s on to the next thing because [he] gave that one thing everything [he] had,” Green recounted.“And I think it will be very similar with this team. Whenever that point comes, we’re going to know that we gave it everything we got and you move on. But you feel good about moving on. You’re not sick about moving on.”

Golden State has faced more challenges than usual on its way to the top seed in the West. An early-season altercation between Green and Kevin Durant led to speculation that the Warriors would splinter apart, and the upcoming free agency for Durant, Klay Thompson and others threatens to break up a successful core.

“Whether it ends while we’re all together, whether it ends when everyone separates, it’s going to end at some point,” Green said. “That’s the nature of the game we play. The fact of the matter is whenever it ends, I think we maximized. Like, we’re going to have a feeling of we maximized what we could do.”

There’s more Warriors news to pass along:

Golden State’s five-year run of success can be traced back to a playoff loss to the Clippers in 2014, notes Mark Medina of The San Jose Mercury News. After that series, the Warriors decided to fire Mark Jackson and replace him with Steve Kerr. Their young stars learned what it takes to succeed in the postseason, and former All-Star Andre Iguodala agreed to accept a role off the bench.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The Philadelphia 76ers got embarrassed at home in Game 1 of their first round playoff series against the Brooklyn Nets on Saturday, losing 111-102 in a game where they pretty much trailed by double digits the entire way. The home crowd was on them early, booing at various points throughout the game, including when Ben Simmons missed two free throws in the third quarter.

Simmons was not a huge factor. He finished the game with only nine points, but most of those came on open, assisted dunks after the game outcome was largely decided in the fourth quarter. He had three assists to go with three turnovers, and that marks his career low in the postseason. Simmons has been an all-around stat sheet stuffer who does a little bit of everything as a tall point guard except, well, shoot from outside. But in the postseason, good teams can take things away and expose weaknesses. It happened again.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The NBA regular season has ended, but the coaching carousel has just begun with vacancies opening throughout the league. 

The most notable open head coach spot is in Los Angeles after the Lakers parted ways with Luke Walton on Friday. There's another opening in Sacramento, where a prospective head coach will take over for Dave Joerger to lead De'Aaron Fox and the Kings. 

Keep up with the latest NBA coaching and front office rumors below:

• The Lakers have been granted permission to meet with 76ers assistant Monty Williams. It is likely their first interaction with take place over the phone or with Lakers officials flying to meet with Williams. The Sixers are currently in the playoffs. (Adrian Wojnarowski, ESPN)

• Former Cavaliers head coach Ty Lue is a "strong frontrunner" to become the Lakers head coach. (Adrian Wojnarowski, ESPN)

• 76ers assistant Monty Williams is also a candidate in the Lakers head coach search. (Adrian Wojnarowski, ESPN)

• The Kings have "formally" requested to interview Luke Walton for their head coach vacancy. (Marc Stein, New York Times)

• Monty Williams is a candidate for the Kings head coach opening as well as Los Angeles'. (Sam Amick, The Athletic)

• Former Cavaliers GM David Griffin will become the Pelicans general manager. (Adrian Wojnarowski, ESPN)
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Steph Curry was tight-lipped after Saturday’s playoff win regarding why he changed one of his shoes during the game.

RELATED: Warriors win

Curry started Game 1 of the Golden State Warriors’ playoff series against the Los Angeles Clippers wearing bright yellow shows. At some point late in the game he changed shoes and was wearing a mismatched pair. His left shoe remained yellow, but his right shoe was all black.
Curry was asked about the shoe change following the game by ABC’s Lisa Salters, but offered very little in response.

“I’m going to keep that to myself,” he said. “It looks good though.”

Let the speculation begin. Curry sprained his right ankle prior to the end of the regular season, and that’s the shoe he changed.

His ankle still giving him trouble will likely be a popular theory. Since it was brought up postgame, we can probably expect there to be further digging and details released in the coming days.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Toronto Raptors forward OG Anunoby may not return until the Eastern Conference finals at the earliest, provided the club makes it that far, following an emergency appendectomy Thursday, sources told ESPN's Adrian Wojnarowski.

The Raptors announced Thursday that Anunoby would be out "indefinitely" following the procedure, though reports specified he would miss a minimum of two weeks. The conference finals likely wouldn't begin until mid-May though, potentially pushing the 21-year-old's recovery timetable to a month.

Toronto faces the Orlando Magic in the opening round and would potentially take on either the Philadelphia 76ers or the Brooklyn Nets in the conference semifinals.

Anunoby averaged 7.0 points and 2.9 rebounds in 67 games with the Raptors in his sophomore season.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
His 7-foot body had crumpled to the bathroom floor again, his head hanging over the toilet, the smell of alcohol oozing from his pores.

Greg Oden had been drinking all day, morning until night, as he did every day. He would take his final sip and fall into a dark oblivion every night. He would wake up and go straight for a bottle to get through the next day. Every time he ate, he would throw up.

The life of the No. 1 pick in the 2007 NBA draft had been whittled down to nothing more than a shell of an existence. Oden huddled in a dark house nearly 10 years after that triumphant moment, isolated, with alcohol-induced bulimia.

Oden, then 28, would stare at the television screen, watching clips of the player drafted No. 2 behind him, Kevin Durant, now a league superstar. The tears would flow.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Let's face it, the Warriors are favored to win the NBA Finals this year, and it makes sense.

After all, Golden State has made it to the championship four years in a row, and it's won three of those times.

Players and fans alike have racked their brains for the past few seasons, asking themselves what could dethrone a team that's not only maintained an amazing core group, but continued to get better.

Things could get interesting this year though. So here are 11 reasons to root for someone other than Golden State.

1. Someone could stop the Warriors' three-peat
The Warriors have won the last two NBA championships and have a chance to make it three straight in 2019. If they do so, they'll become the fourth franchise in NBA history to accomplish the feat.

Los Angeles did it once in Minneapolis, MN, before doing it again after moving to California. Boston won an unmatchable eight straight during its prime years in the early 60's. Lastly, the Bulls were able to three-peat twice under the leadership of the legendary Michael Jordan.

Golden State has been dominant in recent memory, but a loss this year could keep its current group from ascending to the pinnacle of basketball.

Frankly, people are getting tired of the same storyline in the postseason. But not everyone is rooting against the reigning champs.

2. Defeat could spark a Golden State breakup
There's been plenty of speculation about whether this is the last season the Warriors can keep Kevin Durant, Stephen Curry, Klay Thompson and Draymond Green together.

Rumors are swirling Durant wants to move to New York to begin a new journey, since he's already won back-to-back MVP awards in the NBA Finals.

Like Durant, Thompson could likely be looking to get a big payday with a max contract after the season.

Tempers flared between Green and Durant early in the season, which added more fuel to the fire. And if that's not enough drama for you, add DeMarcus Cousins into the mix.

Many question why any player would want to leave such an ideal situation, but imploding on the biggest stage might just send players separate ways. That could make the league a lot more interesting moving forward.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The next Los Angeles Lakers coach will be the franchise’s sixth since Phil Jackson last coached the team in 2011.

As high-pressure, high-profile coveted jobs go, this one is at the top of the list now that that Lakers have parted ways with Luke Walton after three seasons.

The Lakers are a franchise desperate for success after six consecutive seasons without a playoff appearance.

And the next coach is an important hire for the franchise. Los Angeles has LeBron James, but he is 34, and there are only so many elite seasons left. Plus, the Lakers need to fast-track the development of their young core and bring in another All-Star.

The front office, led right now by general manager Rob Pelinka after Magic Johnson’s abrupt resignation Tuesday, and owner Jeanie Buss can’t miss on the coaching hire.

It’s early in the process, but here's a look at potential candidates.

Tyronn Lue

The former Cleveland coach, who took over for David Blatt in 2016 and helped the Cavaliers to the 2016 championship, is close with James. He was 128-83 with the Cavs and also reached the Finals in 2017 and 2018, losing to Golden State both times. A former player who won a championship with the Lakers, Lue started the 2018-19 season with Cleveland but was dismissed after an 0-6 start.

MORE NBA:

Ranking all 16 teams before start of playoffs
Students at LeBron James' I Promise School generating 'extraordinary' results
NBA playoff predictions: Can anyone beat Warriors?
Monty Williams

The Philadelphia 76ers assistant will have multiple suitors, including Sacramento and likely the Lakers. Williams is back in the market for a job after working his way back into it following the death of his wife in 2016. Respected throughout the league, Williams has been an assistant, associate head coach and head coach (New Orleans). He spent 2016-17 and 2017-18 as a front office executive with San Antonio and then took the Philadelphia job before this season. ESPN reported the search will focus on Lue and Williams initially.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The NBA playoffs are upon us, a six-month slog about to finish with a two-month sprint to the title. The slog has been anything but predictable, and the playoffs should be compelling. Here are a few of the top figures and storylines as eight weeks of no sleep are 24 hours away.

James Harden
A trip to the NBA Finals would do more for James Harden’s standing in history and today’s hierarchy any other player. But that would mean carrying the Rockets past the two-time defending champion Golden State Warriors in a likely second-round matchup, not the conference finals, the latest scene of Harden’s tank running on E.

And that would mean Harden reversing course on a very ugly pattern, closing out series in a forgettable manner because going 6-for-36 —as he did in Games 6 and 7 of the West finals combined — won’t cut it at any stage this time around.

Harden is a co-favorite to win Most Valuable Player, which would turn into a dubious honor of sorts if he were to capture the award over Milwaukee’s Giannis Antetokounmpo, only to have the Rockets come up short yet again. Name a two-time MVP who was unable to take his team to the NBA Finals.

That would be Steve Nash, who was coached by the man who patrols the sidelines in Houston, Mike D’Antoni.

Make no mistake, Harden has been magnificent this season. Since the Rockets started 11-14, Harden has played out of his mind, at levels only documented by grainy film and basketball-reference.com. Averaging 38.5 points, 7.2 assists and 7.1 rebounds is impressive no matter the era, style or motivations. But great production comes with great responsibility, to play off the old “Spider-Man” troupe.

His season doesn’t alleviate pressure; it enhances it. And if the Warriors are as vulnerable as Harden and the Rockets like to believe they are, falling to Golden State again would be a crushing failure. And should Harden follow suit from past closing performances, the tone won’t be that Harden saved the Rockets from destruction but that he lacks the true moxie of a champion, that his numbers are empty and he’s not worthy of to be included in a conversation of the greats until he surpasses this roadblock.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
STONY BROOK, N.Y. (AP) The Rio Grande Valley Vipers are G League champions for the third time.

Isaiah Hartenstein scored 30 points, Dakarai Tucker and Michael Frazier each added 24 and the Vipers - the Houston Rockets' affiliate - never trailed on the way to beating the Long Island Nets 129-112 on Friday night in Game 3 of the G League Finals.

Gary Payton II added 17 for the Vipers. Rio Grande Valley won the series 2-1, and added this title to ones the franchise claimed in 2010 and 2013 when what's now the G League was known as the NBA Development League.

A 24-2 run in the second quarter put the game away for the Vipers, who lost Game 1 of the title series before rallying to win the title.

Hartenstein made a pair of 3-pointers in an early 8-0 run that put the Vipers up 30-16, and the barrage in the second quarter left no doubt. Jordan Johnson scored 10 points in the 24-2 spurt, including the first seven - those coming in a span of 52 seconds.

Alan Williams scored 26 points, Dzanan Musa had 24 and Jordan McLaughlin added 22 for Long Island. The Nets, Brooklyn's affiliate, and the Vipers were among four teams who were tied for the G League's best regular-season record at 34-16.

The G League had 27 teams this season, and will grow to 28 next season.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The Milwaukee Bucks are in unfamiliar territory with home-court advantage throughout the NBA playoffs.

Surely being the favorite in the Eastern Conference brings some heightened anxiety.

“The playoffs bring pressure," Bucks coach Mike Budenholzer said Friday. "Now is the time when you’ve got to execute defensively and offensively.

"There’s no 'two weeks from now we need to get better' or 'a month from now.' Every team feels that pressure, the sense of the playoffs. I think our guys are excited about that and the coaching staff the same.”

The Bucks open the postseason against the Detroit Pistons at 6 p.m. on Sunday at Fiserv Forum

Last season, the Bucks were the seventh-seeded team and fell to the Boston Celtics in seven games. In 2016-17, Milwaukee lost in six games to the Toronto Raptors.

The Bucks haven't won a playoff series since 2001.

"As a team we know what our goal is," Bucks forward Giannis Antetokounmpo said. "We haven't recently been out of the first round. We have to take it step by step. 

"Got to win the first game on Sunday, then we can move on."

Antetokounmpo is the co-favorite for NBA most valuable player alongside the Houston Rockets' James Harden. The Bucks star averaged 27.7 points, 12.5 rebounds and 5.9 assists per game. 

He's not going to let the intensity of the playoffs take away his focus.

"Your emotions are a little bit high now," Antetokounmpo said. "As a player, as Giannis, I try to keep my emotions as down as I can. 

"For me, basketball is basketball. A game is a game. It doesn't matter if expectations are going to be higher. It's going to be a game."

Bucks guard Khris Middleton is taking the same approach. 

"No pressure for us," Middleton said. "We know what's at stake. We know we have to get past the first round. We haven't been (past that) yet.

"Just keep doing what we do. Play the way we play, be who we are. We'll be fine."

The Bucks won 60 games in the regular season. That success gives them the home-court edge they have been missing in recent playoff series, easing the pressure a bit. 

"Game 1 and 2 are huge, get off to a great start in the series in front of our home crowd," Middleton said. "That's what Boston did to us last year. Toronto and Chicago in years past."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
It’s not clear how far the Lakers and Bulls got in their discussions about Lonzo Ball back at the 2019 NBA trade deadline, but this means that there is another suitor out there who might have interest in the former No. 2 pick.

In the midst of all the Anthony Davis drama surrounding the Lakers at the 2019 NBA trade deadline, Lonzo Ball made it clear that he did not want to end up on the New Orleans Pelicans when the dust settled, with reports surfacing that he preferred to be dealt to the Chicago Bulls or New York Knicks, with the Phoenix Sunslater being added to that mix.

But while the Suns were talked about plenty as a possible destination because of their mutual interest and Ball’s camp’s clear desire for him to go there, less consideration was given to the idea of Ball as a Bull because of the seeming lack of movement on that front at the time.

However, according to Joe Cowley of the Chicago Sun Times, the Bulls and Lakers did have discussions about Ball, but it’s unclear how far those talks got:

According to one NBA executive, the Bulls and Lakers did start initial conversations on point guard Lonzo Ball shortly after the Ball camp made it public that the Bulls would be one of his desired destinations if Los Angeles were to move him.

The fact that these talks are sourced to “one NBA executive” rather than an executive with either team doesn’t necessarily mean that neither team leaked it, it just leaves some wiggle room as to where this is coming from, so these reports should possibly be taken with a grain of salt.

That noted, Ball to the Bulls would make some sense. Chicago has a need at point guard, and is exactly the type of young team that would likely be willing to gamble on Ball while his value is low and give him time to develop. It’s not clear what they would give up, or which side backed away from these exploratory talks, though, so it’s hard to gauge how realistic this is, or what the Lakers would be getting. It’s worth noting, however, that there are NBA teams with interest in Ball as this summer continues.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Known for his fiery demeanor on the court - and occasionally off the court - during his playing days, Matt Barnes has become one of the more level-headed but free-speaking commentators on both the NBA and the game of basketball. On a recent episode of Speak For Yourself, Barnes and a group of panelists spoke on LaVar Ball's recent comments suggesting LaMelo would be playing next season in a professional league in either China or Australia.

While the rest of the panelists largely took jabs or made unsubstantiated claims, Barnes offered a well-thought-out response that called into question LaVar's decision-making with regards to his kids and his business practices.

I love the whole….the fact that he's in their lives. A black father in their lives. But that's where it stops for me because I think he completely ruined, or on the way to ruining…Melo is very talented. His dad robbed him of his high school experience. So, instead of winning a state championship a couple weeks ago and playing in the McDonald's (All-American) game last week, he's playing over in Lithuania and this b.s. (JBA) league.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The Milwaukee Bucks are in unfamiliar territory with home-court advantage throughout the NBA playoffs.

Surely being the favorite in the Eastern Conference brings some heightened anxiety.

“The playoffs bring pressure," Bucks coach Mike Budenholzer said Friday. "Now is the time when you’ve got to execute defensively and offensively.

"There’s no 'two weeks from now we need to get better' or 'a month from now.' Every team feels that pressure, the sense of the playoffs. I think our guys are excited about that and the coaching staff the same.”

The Bucks open the postseason against the Detroit Pistons at 6 p.m. on Sunday at Fiserv Forum

Last season, the Bucks were the seventh-seeded team and fell to the Boston Celtics in seven games. In 2016-17, Milwaukee lost in six games to the Toronto Raptors.

The Bucks haven't won a playoff series since 2001.

"As a team we know what our goal is," Bucks forward Giannis Antetokounmpo said. "We haven't recently been out of the first round. We have to take it step by step. 

"Got to win the first game on Sunday, then we can move on."

Antetokounmpo is the co-favorite for NBA most valuable player alongside the Houston Rockets' James Harden. The Bucks star averaged 27.7 points, 12.5 rebounds and 5.9 assists per game. 

He's not going to let the intensity of the playoffs take away his focus.

"Your emotions are a little bit high now," Antetokounmpo said. "As a player, as Giannis, I try to keep my emotions as down as I can. 

"For me, basketball is basketball. A game is a game. It doesn't matter if expectations are going to be higher. It's going to be a game."

Bucks guard Khris Middleton is taking the same approach. 

"No pressure for us," Middleton said. "We know what's at stake. We know we have to get past the first round. We haven't been (past that) yet.

"Just keep doing what we do. Play the way we play, be who we are. We'll be fine."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The next Los Angeles Lakers coach will be the franchise’s sixth since Phil Jackson last coached the team in 2011.

As high-pressure, high-profile coveted jobs go, this one is at the top of the list now that that Lakers have parted ways with Luke Walton after three seasons.

The Lakers are a franchise desperate for success after six consecutive seasons without a playoff appearance.

And the next coach is an important hire for the franchise. Los Angeles has LeBron James, but he is 34, and there are only so many elite seasons left. Plus, the Lakers need to fast-track the development of their young core and bring in another All-Star.

The front office, led right now by general manager Rob Pelinka after Magic Johnson’s abrupt resignation Tuesday, and owner Jeanie Buss can’t miss on the coaching hire.

It’s early in the process, but here's a look at potential candidates.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Let's face it, the Warriors are favored to win the NBA Finals this year, and it makes sense.

After all, Golden State has made it to the championship four years in a row, and it's won three of those times.

Players and fans alike have racked their brains for the past few seasons, asking themselves what could dethrone a team that's not only maintained an amazing core group, but continued to get better.

Things could get interesting this year though. So here are 11 reasons to root for someone other than Golden State.

1. Someone could stop the Warriors' three-peat
The Warriors have won the last two NBA championships and have a chance to make it three straight in 2019. If they do so, they'll become the fourth franchise in NBA history to accomplish the feat.

Los Angeles did it once in Minneapolis, MN, before doing it again after moving to California. Boston won an unmatchable eight straight during its prime years in the early 60's. Lastly, the Bulls were able to three-peat twice under the leadership of the legendary Michael Jordan.

Golden State has been dominant in recent memory, but a loss this year could keep its current group from ascending to the pinnacle of basketball.

Frankly, people are getting tired of the same storyline in the postseason. But not everyone is rooting against the reigning champs.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The NBA playoffs are upon us, a six-month slog about to finish with a two-month sprint to the title. The slog has been anything but predictable, and the playoffs should be compelling. Here are a few of the top figures and storylines as eight weeks of no sleep are 24 hours away.

James Harden
A trip to the NBA Finals would do more for James Harden’s standing in history and today’s hierarchy any other player. But that would mean carrying the Rockets past the two-time defending champion Golden State Warriors in a likely second-round matchup, not the conference finals, the latest scene of Harden’s tank running on E.

And that would mean Harden reversing course on a very ugly pattern, closing out series in a forgettable manner because going 6-for-36 —as he did in Games 6 and 7 of the West finals combined — won’t cut it at any stage this time around.

Harden is a co-favorite to win Most Valuable Player, which would turn into a dubious honor of sorts if he were to capture the award over Milwaukee’s Giannis Antetokounmpo, only to have the Rockets come up short yet again. Name a two-time MVP who was unable to take his team to the NBA Finals.

That would be Steve Nash, who was coached by the man who patrols the sidelines in Houston, Mike D’Antoni.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Allen racked up those 3s over the course of an 18-year career with 11 playoff appearances. It took Curry only 10 seasons and seven trips to the playoffs to break the record.

"That's remarkable, given that he's kind of right in his prime," Warriors head coach Steve Kerr said. "He's got a lot of years left."

Said Warriors forward Draymond Green, "I don't think there's much argument when anyone says he's the greatest shooter of all time. I don't know if you can find many people to argue that."

Curry was recognized during a timeout and received a standing ovation.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
"We took the bait," Kerr said. "[Durant] took the bait, and that's two technicals. You get seven technicals, your seventh one is a suspension in the playoffs. Whether you play four playoff games or 24, seven is the magic number. So he's got four to play with after one game."

Kerr noted the Warriors' coaching staff discussed Beverley's antics with its team in preparation for the series, but the veteran guard still caused havoc.

"That's what Beverley does," Kerr said. "We talked about it for the last couple days. He's a helluva defender, he plays hard, we've got a lot of respect for him -- but you cannot take the bait because that's a bad trade for us. The Clippers have made a lot of good trades this year -- that was probably their best."

Beverley said, "No" when asked after the game whether he was egging on Durant.

"I was just being Pat. It was fun out there," he said. "We competed. I really wish we could've played more without the chippy calls, but I understand it's Game 1 and they're trying to set the tone. But this is the playoffs. People want to come see a good basketball game and not so many fouls, but there's things that we can control."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
DENVER -- Derrick White saw an opening, rose up and threw down a thunderous one-handed dunk all over Paul Millsap that shook the Pepsi Center in the third quarter Saturday.

But that wasn't even the San Antonio point guard's biggest play of the night. Redeeming himself after a turnover he committed with just over a minute left in a tight game, White poked the ball away from Jamal Murray with 2.1 seconds left to allow the San Antonio Spurs to take Game 1 from the Denver Nuggets 101-96 in their best-of-seven first-round series.

The seventh-seeded Spurs stole Game 1 on the road from the second-seeded Nuggets, but it was White who stole the show. Growing up and playing his high school ball not far from Denver before playing at the University of Colorado, White had a homecoming so impressive that it left coach Gregg Popovich impressed. White made 7-of-10 shots and finished with 16 points and five assists in his first playoff start.

Answering a total of four questions combined in his pregame and postgame news conferences, Popovich was effusive when asked about White's night.

"He's spectacular for somebody who got put into that position," said Popovich, who became the winningest head coach and passed Lenny Wilkens with 1,413 career regular-season and playoff victories. "To learn that position with a bunch of new players is really remarkable when he's done what he's done. So hopefully he'll continue to play that way because it's gonna be a long series."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
PHILADELPHIA -- Amir Johnson was busted for showing Philadelphia 76ers All-Star teammate Joel Embiid his cellphone on the bench late in a Game 1 playoff loss to the Brooklyn Nets on Saturday, leading to a fine from the team and an apology from the veteran center.

Johnson was caught by TV cameras sitting on the bench and scrolling through his phone late in the fourth quarter, with the Sixers down 16 points in an eventual 111-102 loss. Johnson showed Embiid something on the phone and then slid it into the pocket of his warm-ups.

EDITOR'S PICKS

After disjointed Game 1 loss, Sixers are feeling the pressure
With Joel Embiid hobbled, Philadelphia's winning formula was thrown off, and the deep run the team expected is off to a false start.

Russell, LeVert leads Nets to Game 1 stunner over 76ers
D'Angelo Russell flashed some postseason magic and Caris LeVert scored 23 to lead the Nets to an impressive 111-102 win over the Philadelphia 76ers on Saturday in Game 1 of their series.

"I just looked down because he said his daughter was extremely sick, and he was checking on her," Embiid said.

Johnson issued an apology a few hours after the team's loss.

"I take full responsibility and will accept the consequences of my actions," he said in a statement after not speaking with the media after the game. "I also apologize to my teammates, the 76ers organization and the fans for the distraction this has caused."

The NBA Operations Manual bans the use of cellular phones on the bench during games. The rule book, under the "Use of Technology" section, says violations will "result in substantial fines and/or suspensions."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
The expectation is that Pelinka likely will speak to Williams on the phone or travel east to meet with him because the 76ers' first-round playoff series against the Brooklyn Nets just started, league sources said.

Williams returned to coaching this season as Brett Brown's top assistant. He spent the previous two years in the San Antonio Spurs' front office following the death of his wife, Ingrid, in early 2016.

Williams left the Oklahoma City Thunder as associate head coach in the aftermath of his wife's death. He and his children relocated to San Antonio, where Williams had extended family.

Before his time with the Thunder, Williams coached the New Orleans Pelicans for five seasons. He reached the playoffs in his first season (2010-11) and his last (2014-15).

He won a gold medal as part of Mike Krzyzewski's USA Basketball coaching staff at the Rio Olympic Games in 2016 and has a history with Lakers star LeBron James.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
MILWAUKEE -- The Oklahoma City Thunder locker room was in good spirits after their win over the Milwaukee Bucks last night. Laughter and good vibes defied miserable weather outside, as driving April snow continued to fall since before tip-off at Fiserv Forum.

The positive feel was justified, as win number 49 on the season ensured the Thunder avoided any chance of running into a Golden State Warriors buzzsaw in the first round, opening up their window for a long playoff run.

The night wasn't totally without drama, as star big man Steven Adams went down on his shoulder with full force on a hard Tim Frazier foul in the second quarter.

Adams would log just over 12 minutes on the night, though he remained typically laid back when ESPN enquired about his condition post-game.

"Yeah feel alright mate, making it work you know?" Adams said with a shrug.

Adams will be critical to the Thunder's post-season hopes, as they look to avenge a first-round exit to the Utah Jazz one-year ago.

Strictly looking at the numbers, the regular-season looks strikingly similar to last year's, with just one win being added to their 48-34 record in 2017-18, though Adams reveals the group's feeling about being in a good place.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
"One doesn't work without the other," Bledsoe said of the luxury of funneling Harden into elite help defenders. "I was forcing him off the 3-point line and trying not to [let Harden] do that step-back. Fortunately, it worked for us."

Could that work for Rockets opponents in the playoffs? Coaches and scouts around the league have their doubts.

"You can't guard him. You can't," an advance scout for an East team said. "You just hope that he misses shots and then the other guys will not beat you. He's going to do what he's going to do. You just hope he misses shots."

Rockets coach Mike D'Antoni strongly agrees with that, as does Harden, who made a case to repeat as MVP by averaging 36.1 points and 7.5 assists per game in what was arguably the best individual offensive season in NBA history. Of the top seasons in which a player has averaged at least 35 points, Harden had by far the highest true shooting percentage (.616) and most assists (7.5 per game).

"He's seen every kind of defense," D'Antoni said. "He might have a bad game. But to think that a team is going to stop him ... it's not going to happen."
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
THE NBA REGULAR season is finally over, and if the signals emanating from locker rooms over the past six months offer any indication, the end couldn't come soon enough. The league wasn't without its feel-good stories -- the ascendant Milwaukee Bucks and Denver Nuggets, Luka 'n' Trae -- but 2018-19 might be best remembered as the NBA's winter of discontent.

The league and those who love it often celebrate the dominance of juicy NBA storylines, but even commissioner Adam Silver conceded a few weeks ago that buzz isn't an end unto itself.

"At some point it does matter what they're saying," Silver said.

What they've been saying about the NBA for the better part of the year is that many of the most talented players and charismatic teams suffer from chronic unhappiness. Maybe, as Silver implied, it's a palpable anxiety driven by social media. Or maybe it's the burden of expectation that comes with stardom in a player-driven league. Maybe this restlessness has always existed, shielded from public scrutiny in an era where the moods of players, coaches and executives weren't so easily conveyed.

It's not as if the pressures of a high-intensity environment caught the NBA by surprise. For years, long before Twitter or the proliferation of free-agency-as-reality-show, smart teams have emphasized chemistry and workplace culture as an antidote to the egos, media glare and competing interests that can derail a perfectly good roster of basketball players. But if culture was supposed to stand as the great buffer to the noise, the past 12 months have served as a profound reminder of its limits in a league where individual stardom carries so much weight.

As the postseason gets underway, the undercurrents that exist in Boston, Golden State, Toronto, Philadelphia and San Antonio -- all places where a premium has been placed on the construction and maintenance of team culture -- will be tested. If that culture has value, now would be a good time to see it activated.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
HILADELPHIA -- About an hour before the Philadelphia 76ers tipped off Game 1 of their first-round series against the Brooklyn Nets on Saturday, Sixers owner Josh Harris tried to project an air of triumph. Only there was plenty of cause for trepidation when examining his team.

Joel Embiid, Philadelphia's force-of-nature center, was a game-time decision because of tendinitis in his left knee -- the same knee that was operated on in 2017 to remove a small portion of frayed meniscus -- and coming into the postseason having sat out 14 of 24 games since the All-Star break.

"It's been a long six years for all of us, but at the end of all this, we've assembled an enormous amount of talent and we're really excited to be on the eve of the playoffs with a team that we think can make a deep playoff run," Harris said.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
AUGUSTA, Ga. -- Citing weather concerns, Augusta National Golf Club has canceled the iconic green jacket ceremony -- if the winner of the 83rd edition of the Masters is crowned on Sunday.

With a strong storm system moving across the state, Masters officials moved up the final round to Sunday morning. Players were going off in threesomes on split tees starting at 7:30 a.m. ET. The leaders -- Italy's Francesco Molinari, at 13-under, has a 2-shot lead over Tony Finau and Tiger Woods -- were scheduled to tee off on No. 1 at 9:20 a.m. ET.
Augusta officials announced Sunday morning that they've canceled the ceremony in order to get patrons and workers off the golf course before inclement weather arrives.

"There will not be a Green Jacket Ceremony on the terrace putting green this afternoon in order to expedite gate closures," an Augusta National official wrote in an email. "Weather permitting, we will have photos with the champion on the putting green following the Butler Cabin Green Jacket presentation."

The Masters hasn't had a Monday finish since 1983, when Spain's Seve Ballesteros won for the second time.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
BEFORE LUKE WALTON could finish the brisk, three-minute walk from the team hotel to StellaNova café for his morning coffee on a lazy Tuesday in Oklahoma City, the Los Angeles Lakers coach was spotted by a couple on the street.

It was the Lakers' final road trip of their season. And this couple had flown in from Australia to see the Lakers face the Thunder.

Walton, hardly incognito with a Lakers cap covering his wavy hair and a sweat suit on his 6-foot-8 frame, stopped to pose for a photo before ducking into the shop for his caffeine fix: medium, black.

"They didn't think they were seeing Alex Caruso and Johnathan Williams when they bought those plane tickets," Walton said with a laugh.

Rather than fighting for playoff seeding in the final games, L.A. was officially eliminated from postseason contention with 10 games left on the schedule. Six straight years with no playoff basketball for the once-proud franchise.

LeBron James was shut down with six games remaining; Brandon Ingram missed the final 19 games; Lonzo Ball missed the final 35 games; Josh Hart missed the final 11. Kyle Kuzma and Tyson Chandler also played sparingly because of injuries.

"It's easy to work hard when things are going well, but to show up and continue to work hard when times are tough, that's what this group has done," Walton said as the season wound down. "And it makes it enjoyable to coach."

That enjoyment will have to come elsewhere now.

The Lakers announced Friday afternoon that the team and Walton had "mutually agreed to part ways." But make no mistake, no matter what the media release said: Walton was fired.

Despite whatever challenges existed, Walton wanted to remain the coach of the Lakers, sources said.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Nikola Jokic became just the fourth player to put up a triple-double in his first career NBA playoffs match. However, the 24-year-old Serbian big wasn’t enough for the Denver Nuggets that lost to the San Antonio Spurs at the Pepsi Center and fell behind, 1-0, in the best-of-seven series.

The Joker ended up with 10 points, 14 boards and 14 assists, but the hosts’ comeback attempt down the stretch was cut short. The Nuggets failed to convert their multiple chances in the final seconds with Jokic himself turning the ball over in a crucial offense.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Nikola Mirotic only played 14 games since acquired by the Milwaukee Bucks. He’s been out for nearly one month with a broken left thumb, but was able to participate in full practice Friday and had a non-contact workout on Saturday. The Montenegrin-Spanish forward expects to suit up for Sunday’s first match of the best-of-seven series against the Detroit Pistons.

The NBA Coach of the Year, Mike Budenholzer, confirmed that Mirotic is expected to play on Sunday, so did his teammates. Giannis Antetokounmpo is also set for action despite his recent injury worries. Ersan Ilyasova is available as well. However, their European teammate, Pau Gasol (left ankle), will remain sidelined alongside Malcolm Brogdon (right foot) and Donte DiVincenzo (left foot).
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Assigned from the Houston Rockets to the Rio Grande Valley Vipers, Isaiah Hartenstein was the MVP of the best-of-three series against the Long Island Nets. The Vipers dropped the first match, but secured the “W” in the next two and were crowned G League Champions for the third time.

The 20-year-old German forward averaged 28 points in the finals including 30 in decisive Game 3. He added 17 boards, three assists, two rejections and one steal in the third game improving his averages to 15.7, 2.3, 1.7 and 0.7, respectively.

Fellow European Dzanan Musa was on the wrong side of the finals despite averaging 20 points, 5 rebounds, 1.7 dimes, 0.3 steals and 0.3 blocks. The 19-year-old Bosnian swingman notched 24 points, six boards and one assist in Game 3.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
RADES (Tunisia) - JS Kairouan edged Etoile Sportive Rades 74-73 in a thrilling encounter at the Salle Tawfik Bouhima de Rades to book the last available slot to the FINAL FOUR. 

Tunisian international Ahmed Dhif and Senegalese centre Maodo Nguirane carried the day with 17 and 16 points respectively to stun the home side on a night that the "green army" will live to remember. 

ES Rades tipped off in high gear to lead the first quarter 16-9. The visitors woke up in the second but ES Rades took 35-27 at the break.

The home fans were caught in between song and cheering their side on enjoying every minute of the action-packed match.
Led by Nguirane, JS Kairouan reduced the 12-point deficit and tied the game 65-up in the last quarter to open the game up and create tension in the stands.

JS Kairouan were visibly hungrier for the win and what it would mean for their title ambitions at the first of asking and indeed they got what they deserved ensuring two wins over their rivals - each by a point having won the first time 68-67.

They now join the reigning champions AS Sale(Morocco), eight-time record African winners Primeiro de Agosto(Angola) and Smouha SC (Egypt) in the FINAL FOUR. 
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Playcallers: Spanish duo Lucas Mondelo and Miguel Mendez will have been planning for this moment all year. Both are class acts and will have their respective game plans ready. Mondelo is after his third title (having won in 2011 with Avenida and 2017 with Kursk) while Mendez is looking to add to his maiden title success last year.

All About That Defense: UMMC Ekaterinburg have conceded fewer than 60 points in four of their last five games in EuroLeague Women and turned off the Sopron offensive tap in the Semis. Dynamo Kursk had already shut down Praha in perhaps even more impressive fashion on Friday and you have to pay tribute to both teams at the defensive end lately. Kursk have also blocked more shots than anyone else.

Under The Radar: Dynamo Kursk beat UMMC in the Russian Premier League last month and it remains to be seen how this might impact, if at all. on this Final matchup.

Key Matchup: Sonja Petrovic caught fire in the Semi-Finals and another great European player in Alba Torrens showed glimpses of her star quality. Either of these two could land MVP honors ahead of favorites Breanna Stewart and Brittney Griner.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
RADES (Tunisia) - Tunisian giants Etoile Sportive Rades will be playing for pride when they take on local rivals JS Kairouan on Saturday evening for a place in the FINAL FOUR of the Africa Basketball League 2019. 

The two-time African finalists are desperate to avenge their first leg narrow loss 69-68 to the "green army" who have in hand vowed to come to the party well armed.

Ziyed Chennoufi and Senegalese star Amadou Mbodji are expected to light up the Salle Tawfik Bouhima Rades and produce a thrilling performance to guide ES Rades to the Final Four of Africa's premier club basketball competition. 

The duo were very key to their unbeaten run in Group B and will be hoping to keep their title hopes alive when they come up against a very stubborn side with nothing much to lose but bragging rights. 
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
Twitter Ads info and privacy
Brandon Wood and former MVP Wayne Arnold scored 18 points apiece with the latter adding eight rebounds. 

The Moroccans can now look at their journey thus far and emphasise to the rest of Africa that indeed their victory last year was not a one-off. It was earned and rightly so. 

AS Sale join Primeiro de Agosto (Angola) and Egypt's Smouha SC in the FINAL FOUR of Africa's premier club basketball competition that has been thrilling thus far and is promising more drama in the business end. 
Playing at home in front of their incredible fans, AS Sale led from the start with a 22-15 lead in the first quarter but tables turned in the second quarter with the visitors taking charge of the game to cut down their deficit to just four points at the break 49-45. 

After the break, as if possessed, Najah commanded his space in the paint and displayed a performance that saw the home fans singing his name at every possession which in turn motivated him to be relentless despite a never-give-up attitude from the Nigerians.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
SOPRON (Hungary) - Co-favorites and powerhouse Russian rivals UMMC Ekaterinburg and Dynamo Kursk will fight it out for the EuroLeague Women 2019 title.

The holders had to work hard to see off Sopron Basket 81-59 as UMMC recovered from a challenging opening 20 minutes when they struggled to impose themselves on the hosts.  

But the second half was a powerful statement of intent for the Final as they used their depth to take down Sopron. Brittney Griner was a colossus for UMMC as she harvested 19 points, 8 boards and swatted three shots. There was also an influential cameo from Courtney Vandersloot who had 15 points, 8 rebounds and 5 assists.
Evgeniia Beliakova summarized the contest from a UMMC perspective and stated: "It was a great game for us for a Semi-Final situation and Sopron are a very good team.

"They play with real passion and they can score very quickly. The first half was difficult, but we found a way to show how we can continue to win together. We told each other in those difficult moments that we had to stay together as a team," she stressed. 

Meanwhile Dynamo Kursk will appear in their second Final after they rode past ZVVZ USK Praha 84-67 off the back of a big combined show from Sonja Petrovic and Breanna Stewart.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
BUENOS AIRES (Argentina) – The second edition of the FIBA Americas Youth Development Program Elite Camp started in Argentina’s National Athletic High-Performance Center (CENARD) and in Club Obras Sanitarias. Expectations are high and the calendar is full of training sessions for the participants.

The YDP will take place until the 14, in Buenos Aires, and will feature 24 high-level youth prospects that were born from 2002 to 2005 and come from Argentina, Chile and Uruguay. It will also bring together 20 young referees from Argentina, Chile, Uruguay, Paraguay and Panama.
This is the second YDP edition and this time it will take place in the National Athletic High-Performance Center (CENARD) and in Obras Sanitarias, in the capital city of Buenos Aires, Argentina, from April 11 to 14, 2019.

“I'm very happy and I have no words to express in the face of this great opportunity. I think they chose me because of my effort, how much I want to play, and this is a very beautiful feeling that I must make the most out of. The first day was active, we warmed up, they evaluated our jumps, and we had a media day, where they took our pictures,” said 6’3” Argentine player Tomás Allende, who’s one of the young prospects that were chosen for the Camp.
FIBA Americas and the Argentine Basketball Confederation are the hosts for this edition. The entire program will include several camps and will develop young talents, based on three pillars: bolstering a greater access to basketball for young athletes, granting them more opportunities to develop their game, and creating a platform for young elite players in the Americas.

To close the first day of the camp, the players underwent anthropometric measurements and physical evaluations. 
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
SOPRON (Hungary) - Maybe it is written in the stars that Breanna Stewart is destined for MVP and a EuroLeague Women winners' medal in her rookie season.

Voted the Regular Season MVP by fans, she wasted little time in making a big impression at her first Final Four as she chases the jaw-dropping prospect of capturing a staggering array of MVP titles inside 12 months.

Her spectacular 32-point haul against ZVVZ USK Praha carried Dynamo Kursk into only their second ever Final. Now she is one major performance and possible victory away from maybe adding another gong to the WNBA , WNBA Finals and FIBA Women's Basketball World Cup MVP accolades she already has on her resume.
However, when she walked off the floor after torching Praha, it was Sonja Petrovic she wanted to talk about. Her colleague, having had a relatively quiet campaign, also exploded, with the Serbian forward adding 20 points.

"When we needed Sonja in that second quarter, she really started to get hot and was getting really aggressive," enthused Stewart.

"Our team all know what kind of level of player Sonia is and we all came together to get a tough win - it was a lot more difficult than the score says."

As well as heaping praise on Petrovic, she also spoke with enthusiasm about her Seattle teammate Natasha Howard, who was a mid-season arrival at Kursk. The center contributed a sparkling double-double of 22 points and 10 boards.

She said: "To bring 'Tash' to the club was just awesome for me being so familiar with her.

"We play really well together and she was another player who did what she needed to do in this important Semi-Final," added Stewart.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
SAN JUAN - With the participation of 6,100 players and 485 teams divided in 12 sections, the Puerto Rico Basketball Federation’s annual Mini Basketball Tournament began this past weekend.

The tournament features categories for boys aged seven through fourteen and will last from April 6 to the month of June.

“The tournament began with 485 teams this year and we're working with (children of) the ages of 7 to 14,” said to FIBA.basketball the tournament's General Director, Mr. Iván Vázquez.

This year’s edition will see some changes that were approved in order to foster a holistic improvement of the participants. Another objective is to create better citizens through activities that develop their character and their capability of relating to others.

“At seven years of age, we don’t register in the scoreboard, they're just playing with the clock,” Vázquez explained. “Basically, as part of the Federation’s vision, we're bolstering the individual defense in the younger categories, and the individual defense was established as part of the rules. Zone defense isn’t allowed, except for the little [7-8 categories]. From 9 to 14 it’s an individual defense, as part of the development the Federation wants to do.”

Some of these ideas are the result of the federations’ participation in the Americas Mini Basketball Congress, which took place in Hermosillo, Mexico, on February. This was a four-day encounter where discussions around issues and tactical matters where hosted around the goal of teaching children to love basketball to secure the sport's future.

“I participated in that congress and several ideas came out of it, but the tournament already had its rules. I already have some ideas that I want to implement next year based on what I witnessed in the congress. In the small categories we want more recreation and less competition. We're also evaluating the 3x3 modality for the younger [7-8] categories.”

FBPUR's tournament features coaches and trainers that are prepared to work with children and young players, as well as referees and table officials that guarantee that games run according to the rules.

“The Federation, by means of its Technical Commission, certifies the coaches. They must evidence continual education courses, and those that aren't certified must do so,” assured the tournament's director.
</BODY>
</REUTERS>
<REUTERS>
<SPORT>basketball</SPORT>
<BODY>
WUXI (China) – Serbian powerhouse Liman (SRB) headline a star-studded field at the Wuxi Challenger on April 13-14.

World No.1 Liman will start the first professional event of the season as favorites but face a tough challenge against some of the best 3x3 teams in the world.

Riga Ghetto (LAT), who finished runners-up at the FIBA 3x3 World Tour Bloomage Beijing Final last year, loom as their main challengers as the No.2 seed while Amsterdam (NED), Zemun (SRB) and Gagarin (RUS) are also fancies and round out the top five seeds.

There is the mouth-watering prospect of defending champions Liman and Riga Ghetto clashing in the final in a potential revenge game for the Serbs who were stunningly upset by the Latvians in the quarter-finals in Beijing last start. 
Liman, who have been based in China during the past couple of months, will boast their big names including Stefan Stojacic aka Mr Robot who will be looking to get back on 3x3’s throne after finishing last year second on the individual rankings behind rival Dusan Bulut.

Liman had a sour end to a spectacular 2018, where they won three Masters and finished runners-up three times.  
</BODY>
</REUTERS>